<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Nickels on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/eric-nickels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Nickels on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/eric-nickels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA methylation at birth in monozygotic twins discordant for pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aberrant DNA methylation constitutes a key feature of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia at diagnosis, however its role as a predisposing or early contributor to leukemia development remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we evaluate DNA methylation at birth in 41 leukemia-discordant monozygotic twin pairs using the Illumina EPIC array on archived neonatal blood spots to identify epigenetic variation associated with development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia, independent of genetic influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through conditional logistic regression we identify 240 significant probes and 10 regions associated with the discordant onset of leukemia. We identify a significant negative coefficient bias, indicating DNA hypomethylation in cases, across the array and enhanced in open sea, shelf/shore, and gene body regions compared to promoter and CpG island regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we show an association between global DNA hypomethylation and future development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia across disease-discordant genetically identical twins, implying DNA hypomethylation may contribute more generally to leukemia risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
