<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qianxi Feng on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/qianxi-feng/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qianxi Feng on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/qianxi-feng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Periconceptional folate intake influences DNA methylation at birth based on dietary source in an analysis of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia cases and controls</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aberrant DNA methylation constitutes a key feature of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia at diagnosis, however its role as a predisposing or early contributor to leukemia development remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we evaluate DNA methylation at birth in 41 leukemia-discordant monozygotic twin pairs using the Illumina EPIC array on archived neonatal blood spots to identify epigenetic variation associated with development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia, independent of genetic influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through conditional logistic regression we identify 240 significant probes and 10 regions associated with the discordant onset of leukemia. We identify a significant negative coefficient bias, indicating DNA hypomethylation in cases, across the array and enhanced in open sea, shelf/shore, and gene body regions compared to promoter and CpG island regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we show an association between global DNA hypomethylation and future development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia across disease-discordant genetically identical twins, implying DNA hypomethylation may contribute more generally to leukemia risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatal cytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between HLA genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups.
For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio [OR] = 0.59; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.49-0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient = 0.13; 95% CI, 0.04-0.22).
HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR = 0.63; 95% CI, 0.38-1.01), although they had a lower tumor necrosis factor-α level (coefficient = −0.27; 95% CI, −0.49 to −0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk or cytokine levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
