<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Qian Zhang on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/qian-zhang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Qian Zhang on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/qian-zhang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and Pathological Features of Prostatic Stromal Tumor of Uncertain Malignant Potential: A Retrospective Study of 23 Chinese Cases</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Prostatic stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) is a rare disease that may coexist with prostate stromal sarcoma (PSS). We aimed to analyze the histological and clinical features of STUMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Twenty-three patients diagnosed with STUMP from 2008 to 2019 were included. Clinicopathological and follow-up information was collected. In the subgroup analysis, we divided the patients into a pure STUMP group (N = 18) and a mixed STUMP (STUMP coexisting with PSS) group (N = 5). Student&amp;rsquo;s t test was used to compare the 2 groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Patients had a mean age of 55.5 ± 19.4 years and an average follow-up time of 42.3 months. The mean prostate volume was 109.2 ± 73.5 cm3, and the mean prostate-specific antigen was 8.03 ± 10.5 ng/mL. In the subgroup analysis, 16.7% (2/12) of pure STUMP patients had disease progression, while 100% (3/3) of mixed STUMP patients suffered from recurrence. Compared with the pure STUMP group, the mixed STUMP group was younger (37.2 vs. 60.6 years, p = 0.013) and had lower expression of estrogen receptor and progesterone receptor (p = 0.004 and p &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: STUMP is a rare disease with a relatively good prognosis. However, there is still a possibility of disease progression or coexistence with stromal sarcoma. Timely diagnosis and regular monitoring may be helpful in improving treatment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Hyperplasia; Prognosis; Prostate; Stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inflammation patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: The distribution characteristics of inflammatory cells in hyperplastic prostatic tissue and its influences on disease development remain unknown. We aimed to explore the infiltration characteristics of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) in combination with clinical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: The present study included 76 cases of BPH patients underwent transurethral resection of prostate (TURP). Hematoxylin-eosin staining was performed to identify the degree of general inflammation in prostatic tissues. The infiltration of T-lymphocytes (CD3), B-lymphocytes (CD20), and macrophages (CD68) were recorded by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The present study included 76 BPH patients with the mean age of 69.5 years old (range, 49-83 years) and the mean prostate volume of 91.9 mL (range, 24-218 mL). Periglandular inflammation was the most common pattern, being presented in 94.7% (72/76) patients, followed by stromal inflammation (67/76, 88.2%) and glandular inflammation (57/76, 75.0%). However, the stroma presented the highest rate of severe inflammation (14.6%). And the grades of glandular inflammation and stromal inflammation were independently correlated with prostate volume. T-lymphocytes, B-lymphocytes and macrophages had different infiltrated patterns in histological structures of prostate. And stromal hyperplasia dominated BPH was only significantly correlated with the T-lymphocytes infiltration condition (P=0.001). Meanwhile, overweight patients had more severe glandular inflammation in the prostate (P=0.010). The grade of glandular inflammation could independently increase prostate-specific antigen (PSA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We characterized infiltrated patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues from surgically treated BPH specimens. The role of inflammation in BPH development was highlighted by its correlation with the prostate volume, metabolism and PSA level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: B-lymphocytes; Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH); T-lymphocytes; inflammation; macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic syndrome is associated with improved cancer-specific survival in patients with localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Metabolic syndrome (MetS) has been found to be prevalent in cancer and have implications in cancer outcomes. In this study, we attempted to evaluate the prognostic value of MetS in localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC) patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We retrospectively collected clinicopathological data and pre-treatment laboratory test results of 480 patients with localized (T1-2N0M0) ccRCC undergoing radical or partial nephrectomy in Peking University First Hospital. MetS was diagnosed by criteria of the 2004 Chinese Medical Association Diabetes Society. Univariate and multivariate analyses were conducted to analyze the association between clinicopathological characteristics, MetS, and disease outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: In our cohort, 136 patients (28.3%) were diagnosed with MetS. Among them, 113 (83.1%) were men, suggesting that men were more likely to have MetS. This syndrome was also associated with increased pre-treatment creatinine levels. Median follow-up time was 70 months (range, 1-118 months) and 5-year overall survival (OS) rate was 92%. MetS was an independent favorable factor of cancer-specific survival (CSS) (P=0.017), and similar results were observed in Fuhrman nuclear grade 1-2 ccRCC patients by further analysis. Neither of the four components of the MetS (hypertension, diabetes mellitus, overweight/obesity and dyslipidemia) was an independent predictor of CSS. Patients who met more than 3 of the 4 criteria for MetS had higher CSS than those who met fewer than 2 criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: MetS is an independent prognostic factor for better CSS in localized ccRCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Metabolic syndrome (MetS); cancer-specific survival (CSS); prognosis; renal cell carcinoma (RCC).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
