<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice Y. Kang on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/alice-y.-kang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alice Y. Kang on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/alice-y.-kang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome-Wide Association Study of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children with Down Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome (DS) is caused by constitutional trisomy of chromosome 21 and is associated with an up to 30-fold increased risk of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL). While DS is associated with alterations in epigenetic markers, including DNA methylation, and gene expression. These mechanisms have not been fully explored in relation to DS-ALL etiology. Because the epigenome is sensitive to genetic and environmental influences during fetal development and can be leveraged to characterize blood cell proportions, we sought to evaluate the role of the neonatal methylome in children with DS on subsequent ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome-Wide Association Study of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children with Down Syndrome (Conference)</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Down syndrome (DS) is associated with an up to 30-fold increased risk of B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), and DS-ALL patients have worse overall survival and increased long-term treatment-related health conditions compared with non-DS ALL patients. In a recent genome-wide association study of DS-ALL, established ALL genetic risk loci were associated with DS-ALL, with several single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) conferring a larger effect on ALL risk in the context of DS than in euploidy. We performed an epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) to elucidate whether epigenetic differences at birth are associated with risk of subsequent DS-ALL.
Methods: The DS-ALL Discovery Study included 147 DS-ALL cases and 198 DS controls from the International Study of Down Syndrome Acute Leukemia, with newborn dried bloodspots (DBS) obtained from California (n=326) and Washington state (n=19) biobanks. The DS-ALL Replication Study included 24 DS-ALL cases and 24 DS controls with newborn DBS from the Michigan Neonatal Biobank. DNA was isolated from DBS, bisulfite converted, and assayed using Illumina Infinium MethylationEPIC Beadchip genome-wide DNA methylation arrays. Raw data were processed using “minfi” and “noob” packages in R. Reference-based deconvolution of blood cell proportions was performed using the Identifying Optimal DNA methylation Libraries (IDOL) algorithm, using DNA methylation data from cord blood reference samples, to estimate proportions of B cells, T cells (CD4+ and CD8+), monocytes, granulocytes, natural killer cells, and nucleated red blood cells. We compared each cell type proportion between DS-ALL cases and DS controls using linear regression adjusting for sex, plate, and principal components (PCs) to account for genetic ancestry. To identify single CpG probes associated with DS-ALL risk, we performed a multiethnic EWAS of DS-ALL in each study using linear regression adjusting for sex, plate, and PCs related to: 1) cell-type proportions and 2) genetic ancestry. Differentially methylated regions (DMRs) were identified using DMRcate and comb-p methods. In the Discovery Study, genome-wide SNP array data were available for 131 cases and 130 controls, and data from targeted sequencing of somatic mutations in exons 2/3 of GATA1 were available for 184/198 DS controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Deconvolution of blood cell proportions in the DS-ALL Discovery Study showed significantly higher B cell proportions in newborns with DS who later developed ALL (mean=0.0128, sd=0.0151) compared with DS controls (mean=0.00826, sd=0.0115) (P=6.4x10-4, coefficient=0.0052). A significantly higher B cell proportion at birth was also found in DS-ALL cases in the independent Replication Study (cases mean=0.048, sd=0.024; controls mean=0.039, sd=0.028; P=0.03, coefficient=0.015). In the Discovery Study, the B cell difference remained significant (P=5.8x10-3) with a similar effect size (coefficient=0.0045) after removal of GATA1 mutation-positive DS controls (n=30). We also investigated whether DS-ALL risk SNPs at ARID5B, IKZF1, GATA3, and CDKN2A may confound the association, but the increased B cell proportions in DS-ALL remained significant and effect estimates slightly increased in SNP genotype-adjusted models (coefficient range:0.0055-0.0059). In the EWAS of DS-ALL, 9 CpGs reached epigenome-wide significance (P&amp;lt;7.67x10-8), including 2 CpGs overlapping the promoter of the tumor suppressor gene TRIM13, frequently deleted in B-CLL, although none of these showed evidence of association (P&amp;lt;0.05) in the Replication Study. We identified 125 DMRs associated with DS-ALL in the Discovery Study. For 3 DMRs, overlapping genes HOPX, SMIM24, and PPP1R10, all implicated in normal and leukemic stem cell function, there were multiple significant CpGs in the Replication Study (P&amp;lt;0.05) all with effects in the same direction as the Discovery Study DMRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Increased B cell proportions in newborns with DS may be a risk factor for development of DS-ALL in childhood. This finding, based on DNA methylation data, requires confirmation using conventional cell count measures, and should be explored as a novel biomarker for ALL risk in the non-DS population. Single CpGs and DMRs associated with DS-ALL risk in our Discovery Study require further investigation, including in additional ALL case-control studies in DS and non-DS populations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Biomarkers of Prenatal Tobacco Smoke Exposure Are Associated with Gene Deletions in Childhood Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Parental smoking is implicated in the etiology of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), the most common childhood cancer. We recently reported an association between an epigenetic biomarker of early-life tobacco smoke exposure at the AHRR gene and increased frequency of somatic gene deletions among ALL cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Here, we further assess this association using two epigenetic biomarkers for maternal smoking during pregnancy-DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and a recently established polyepigenetic smoking score-in an expanded set of 482 B-cell ALL (B-ALL) cases in the California Childhood Leukemia Study with available Illumina 450K or MethylationEPIC array data. Multivariable Poisson regression models were used to test the associations between the epigenetic biomarkers and gene deletion numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: We found an association between DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and deletion number among 284 childhood B-ALL cases with MethylationEPIC array data, with a ratio of means (RM) of 1.31 [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.02-1.69] for each 0.1 β value reduction in DNA methylation, an effect size similar to our previous report in an independent set of 198 B-ALL cases with 450K array data [meta-analysis summary RM (sRM) = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.10-1.57]. The polyepigenetic smoking score was positively associated with gene deletion frequency among all 482 B-ALL cases (sRM = 1.31 for each 4-unit increase in score; 95% CI, 1.09-1.57).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We provide further evidence that prenatal tobacco-smoke exposure may influence the generation of somatic copy-number deletions in childhood B-ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact: Analyses of deletion breakpoint sequences are required to further understand the mutagenic effects of tobacco smoke in childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
