<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muqiu Zhang on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/muqiu-zhang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Muqiu Zhang on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/muqiu-zhang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The inflammation patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: The distribution characteristics of inflammatory cells in hyperplastic prostatic tissue and its influences on disease development remain unknown. We aimed to explore the infiltration characteristics of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) in combination with clinical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: The present study included 76 cases of BPH patients underwent transurethral resection of prostate (TURP). Hematoxylin-eosin staining was performed to identify the degree of general inflammation in prostatic tissues. The infiltration of T-lymphocytes (CD3), B-lymphocytes (CD20), and macrophages (CD68) were recorded by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The present study included 76 BPH patients with the mean age of 69.5 years old (range, 49-83 years) and the mean prostate volume of 91.9 mL (range, 24-218 mL). Periglandular inflammation was the most common pattern, being presented in 94.7% (72/76) patients, followed by stromal inflammation (67/76, 88.2%) and glandular inflammation (57/76, 75.0%). However, the stroma presented the highest rate of severe inflammation (14.6%). And the grades of glandular inflammation and stromal inflammation were independently correlated with prostate volume. T-lymphocytes, B-lymphocytes and macrophages had different infiltrated patterns in histological structures of prostate. And stromal hyperplasia dominated BPH was only significantly correlated with the T-lymphocytes infiltration condition (P=0.001). Meanwhile, overweight patients had more severe glandular inflammation in the prostate (P=0.010). The grade of glandular inflammation could independently increase prostate-specific antigen (PSA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We characterized infiltrated patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues from surgically treated BPH specimens. The role of inflammation in BPH development was highlighted by its correlation with the prostate volume, metabolism and PSA level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: B-lymphocytes; Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH); T-lymphocytes; inflammation; macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
