<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Keren Xu on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/keren-xu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Keren Xu on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/keren-xu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated epigenetic aging in newborns with Down syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerated aging is a hallmark of Down syndrome (DS), with adults experiencing early-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and premature aging of the skin, hair, and immune and endocrine systems. Accelerated epigenetic aging has been found in the blood and brain tissue of adults with DS but when premature aging in DS begins remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated whether accelerated aging in DS is already detectable in blood at birth. We assessed the association between age acceleration and DS using five epigenetic clocks in 346 newborns with DS and 567 newborns without DS using Illumina MethylationEPIC DNA methylation array data. We compared two epigenetic aging clocks (DNAmSkinBloodClock and pan-tissue DNAmAge) and three epigenetic gestational age clocks (Haftorn, Knight, and Bohlin) between DS and non-DS newborns using linear regression adjusting for observed age, sex, batch, deconvoluted blood cell proportions, and genetic ancestry. Targeted sequencing of GATA1 was performed in a subset of 184 newborns with DS to identify somatic mutations associated with transient abnormal myelopoiesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DS was significantly associated with increased DNAmSkinBloodClock (effect estimate = 0.2442, p &amp;lt; 0.0001), with an epigenetic age acceleration of 244 days in newborns with DS after adjusting for potential confounding factors (95% confidence interval: 196–292 days). We also found evidence of epigenetic age acceleration associated with somatic GATA1 mutations among newborns with DS (p = 0.015). DS was not associated with epigenetic gestational age acceleration. We demonstrate that accelerated epigenetic aging in the blood of DS patients begins prenatally, with implications for the pathophysiology of immunosenescence and other aging-related traits in DS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Biomarkers of Prenatal Tobacco Smoke Exposure Are Associated with Gene Deletions in Childhood Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Parental smoking is implicated in the etiology of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), the most common childhood cancer. We recently reported an association between an epigenetic biomarker of early-life tobacco smoke exposure at the AHRR gene and increased frequency of somatic gene deletions among ALL cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Here, we further assess this association using two epigenetic biomarkers for maternal smoking during pregnancy-DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and a recently established polyepigenetic smoking score-in an expanded set of 482 B-cell ALL (B-ALL) cases in the California Childhood Leukemia Study with available Illumina 450K or MethylationEPIC array data. Multivariable Poisson regression models were used to test the associations between the epigenetic biomarkers and gene deletion numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: We found an association between DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and deletion number among 284 childhood B-ALL cases with MethylationEPIC array data, with a ratio of means (RM) of 1.31 [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.02-1.69] for each 0.1 β value reduction in DNA methylation, an effect size similar to our previous report in an independent set of 198 B-ALL cases with 450K array data [meta-analysis summary RM (sRM) = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.10-1.57]. The polyepigenetic smoking score was positively associated with gene deletion frequency among all 482 B-ALL cases (sRM = 1.31 for each 4-unit increase in score; 95% CI, 1.09-1.57).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We provide further evidence that prenatal tobacco-smoke exposure may influence the generation of somatic copy-number deletions in childhood B-ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact: Analyses of deletion breakpoint sequences are required to further understand the mutagenic effects of tobacco smoke in childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
