<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zhaohui Zhou on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/zhaohui-zhou/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zhaohui Zhou on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/zhaohui-zhou/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and Pathological Features of Prostatic Stromal Tumor of Uncertain Malignant Potential: A Retrospective Study of 23 Chinese Cases</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Prostatic stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) is a rare disease that may coexist with prostate stromal sarcoma (PSS). We aimed to analyze the histological and clinical features of STUMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Twenty-three patients diagnosed with STUMP from 2008 to 2019 were included. Clinicopathological and follow-up information was collected. In the subgroup analysis, we divided the patients into a pure STUMP group (N = 18) and a mixed STUMP (STUMP coexisting with PSS) group (N = 5). Student&amp;rsquo;s t test was used to compare the 2 groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Patients had a mean age of 55.5 ± 19.4 years and an average follow-up time of 42.3 months. The mean prostate volume was 109.2 ± 73.5 cm3, and the mean prostate-specific antigen was 8.03 ± 10.5 ng/mL. In the subgroup analysis, 16.7% (2/12) of pure STUMP patients had disease progression, while 100% (3/3) of mixed STUMP patients suffered from recurrence. Compared with the pure STUMP group, the mixed STUMP group was younger (37.2 vs. 60.6 years, p = 0.013) and had lower expression of estrogen receptor and progesterone receptor (p = 0.004 and p &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: STUMP is a rare disease with a relatively good prognosis. However, there is still a possibility of disease progression or coexistence with stromal sarcoma. Timely diagnosis and regular monitoring may be helpful in improving treatment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Hyperplasia; Prognosis; Prostate; Stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
