<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rong Wang on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/rong-wang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rong Wang on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/rong-wang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatalcytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown, but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions. We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between human leukocyte antigen (HLA) genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II). We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups. For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio, OR=0.59; 95% confidence interval, CI:0.49, 0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient=0.13; 95%CI:0.04, 0.22). HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR=0.63; 95%CI:0.38, 1.01), however with lower TNF-􏰀 level (coefficient=-0.27; 95%CI:-0.49, -0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk, or cytokine levels. The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
