<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric M Nickels on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/eric-m-nickels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric M Nickels on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/eric-m-nickels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Periconceptional folate intake influences DNA methylation at birth based on dietary source in an analysis of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia cases and controls</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
Periconceptional folate intake is associated with the establishment of DNA methylation in offspring; however, variations in this relationship by food sources versus folic acid supplements are not described. Also, maternal folate intake is associated with decreased risk of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), but the mechanism is not known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives
We evaluated the relationship between periconceptional folate intake by source and DNA methylation at birth in a cohort of pediatric ALL cases and controls in an epigenome-wide association study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Genome-wide DNA methylation status obtained from archived neonatal blood spots from pediatric ALL cases (n = 189) and controls (n = 205) in the California Childhood Leukemia Study (CCLS) from 1995–2008 was compared to periconceptional folate from total, food, and supplemental sources using multivariable linear regression. Further stratification was performed by income, education, ethnicity, and total folate intake. We evaluated variable DNA methylation response to periconceptional folate by ALL case status through an interaction term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Two significant differentially methylated probes (DMPs) were associated with food and supplemental periconceptional folate intake in all subjects (n = 394). The top differentially methylated region at the promoter region of DUSP22 demonstrated DNA hypermethylation in ALL cases but not controls in response to total and food folate intake. We further identified eight interaction term DMPs with variable DNA methylation response to folate intake by ALL case status. Further stratification of the cohort by education and ethnicity revealed a substantially higher number of DMPs associated with supplemental folic acid intake in Hispanic subjects with lower income and education level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions
We identified modest associations between periconceptional folate intake and DNA methylation differing by source, including variation by ALL case status. Hispanic subjects of lower income and education appear uniquely responsive to periconceptional folate supplementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
