<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Irene Roberts on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/irene-roberts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Irene Roberts on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/irene-roberts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated epigenetic aging in newborns with Down syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerated aging is a hallmark of Down syndrome (DS), with adults experiencing early-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and premature aging of the skin, hair, and immune and endocrine systems. Accelerated epigenetic aging has been found in the blood and brain tissue of adults with DS but when premature aging in DS begins remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated whether accelerated aging in DS is already detectable in blood at birth. We assessed the association between age acceleration and DS using five epigenetic clocks in 346 newborns with DS and 567 newborns without DS using Illumina MethylationEPIC DNA methylation array data. We compared two epigenetic aging clocks (DNAmSkinBloodClock and pan-tissue DNAmAge) and three epigenetic gestational age clocks (Haftorn, Knight, and Bohlin) between DS and non-DS newborns using linear regression adjusting for observed age, sex, batch, deconvoluted blood cell proportions, and genetic ancestry. Targeted sequencing of GATA1 was performed in a subset of 184 newborns with DS to identify somatic mutations associated with transient abnormal myelopoiesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DS was significantly associated with increased DNAmSkinBloodClock (effect estimate = 0.2442, p &amp;lt; 0.0001), with an epigenetic age acceleration of 244 days in newborns with DS after adjusting for potential confounding factors (95% confidence interval: 196–292 days). We also found evidence of epigenetic age acceleration associated with somatic GATA1 mutations among newborns with DS (p = 0.015). DS was not associated with epigenetic gestational age acceleration. We demonstrate that accelerated epigenetic aging in the blood of DS patients begins prenatally, with implications for the pathophysiology of immunosenescence and other aging-related traits in DS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome-Wide Association Study of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children with Down Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome (DS) is caused by constitutional trisomy of chromosome 21 and is associated with an up to 30-fold increased risk of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL). While DS is associated with alterations in epigenetic markers, including DNA methylation, and gene expression. These mechanisms have not been fully explored in relation to DS-ALL etiology. Because the epigenome is sensitive to genetic and environmental influences during fetal development and can be leveraged to characterize blood cell proportions, we sought to evaluate the role of the neonatal methylome in children with DS on subsequent ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The genome-wide impact of trisomy 21 on DNA methylation and its implications for hematopoiesis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome is associated with genome-wide perturbation of gene expression, which may be mediated by epigenetic changes. We perform an epigenome-wide association study on neonatal bloodspots comparing 196 newborns with Down syndrome and 439 newborns without Down syndrome, adjusting for cell-type heterogeneity, which identifies 652 epigenome-wide significant CpGs (P &amp;lt; 7.67 × 10−8) and 1,052 differentially methylated regions. Differential methylation at promoter/enhancer regions correlates with gene expression changes in Down syndrome versus non-Down syndrome fetal liver hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells (P &amp;lt; 0.0001). The top two differentially methylated regions overlap RUNX1 and FLI1, both important regulators of megakaryopoiesis and hematopoietic development, with significant hypermethylation at promoter regions of these two genes. Excluding Down syndrome newborns harboring preleukemic GATA1 mutations (N = 30), identified by targeted sequencing, has minimal impact on the epigenome-wide association study results. Down syndrome has profound, genome-wide effects on DNA methylation in hematopoietic cells in early life, which may contribute to the high frequency of hematological problems, including leukemia, in children with Down syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
