<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Libby Morimoto on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/libby-morimoto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Libby Morimoto on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/libby-morimoto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatalcytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown, but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions. We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between human leukocyte antigen (HLA) genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II). We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups. For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio, OR=0.59; 95% confidence interval, CI:0.49, 0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient=0.13; 95%CI:0.04, 0.22). HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR=0.63; 95%CI:0.38, 1.01), however with lower TNF-􏰀 level (coefficient=-0.27; 95%CI:-0.49, -0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk, or cytokine levels. The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial 1555 G&gt;A Variant as a Potential Risk Factor for Childhood Glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:
Childhood glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is a highly aggressive disease with low survival, and its etiology, especially concerning germline genetic risk, is poorly understood. Mitochondria play a key role in putative tumorigenic processes relating to cellular oxidative metabolism, and mitochondrial DNA variants were not previously assessed for association with pediatric brain tumor risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods:
We conducted an analysis of 675 mitochondrial DNA variants in 90 childhood GBM cases and 2,789 controls to identify enrichment of mitochondrial variant associated with GBM risk. We also performed this analysis for other glioma subtypes including pilocytic astrocytoma. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants were also analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:
We identified m1555 A&amp;gt;G was significantly associated with GBM risk (adjusted OR 29.30, 95% CI 5.25-163.4, P value 9.5X10 -4). No association was detected for other subtypes. Haplotype analysis further supported the independent risk contributed by m1555 G&amp;gt;A, instead of a haplogroup joint effect. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants identified significant associations in European (rs62036057 in WWOX, adjusted OR = 2.99, 95% CI 1.88-4.75, P value = 3.42X10 -6) and Hispanic (rs111709726 in EFHD1, adjusted OR = 3.57, 95% CI 1.99-6.40, P value = 1.41X10 -6) populations in ethnicity-stratified analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:
We report for the first time a potential role played by a functional mitochondrial ribosomal RNA variant in childhood GBM risk, and a potential role for both mitochondrial and nuclear-mitochondrial DNA polymorphisms in GBM tumorigenesis. These data implicate cellular oxidative metabolic capacity as a contributor to the etiology of pediatric glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Biomarkers of Prenatal Tobacco Smoke Exposure Are Associated with Gene Deletions in Childhood Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Parental smoking is implicated in the etiology of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), the most common childhood cancer. We recently reported an association between an epigenetic biomarker of early-life tobacco smoke exposure at the AHRR gene and increased frequency of somatic gene deletions among ALL cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Here, we further assess this association using two epigenetic biomarkers for maternal smoking during pregnancy-DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and a recently established polyepigenetic smoking score-in an expanded set of 482 B-cell ALL (B-ALL) cases in the California Childhood Leukemia Study with available Illumina 450K or MethylationEPIC array data. Multivariable Poisson regression models were used to test the associations between the epigenetic biomarkers and gene deletion numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: We found an association between DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and deletion number among 284 childhood B-ALL cases with MethylationEPIC array data, with a ratio of means (RM) of 1.31 [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.02-1.69] for each 0.1 β value reduction in DNA methylation, an effect size similar to our previous report in an independent set of 198 B-ALL cases with 450K array data [meta-analysis summary RM (sRM) = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.10-1.57]. The polyepigenetic smoking score was positively associated with gene deletion frequency among all 482 B-ALL cases (sRM = 1.31 for each 4-unit increase in score; 95% CI, 1.09-1.57).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We provide further evidence that prenatal tobacco-smoke exposure may influence the generation of somatic copy-number deletions in childhood B-ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact: Analyses of deletion breakpoint sequences are required to further understand the mutagenic effects of tobacco smoke in childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
