<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-ancestry genome-wide association study of 4,069 children with glioma identifies 9p21.3 risk locus</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
While recent sequencing studies have revealed that 10% of childhood gliomas are caused by rare germline mutations, the role of common variants is undetermined and no genome-wide significant risk loci for pediatric CNS tumors have been identified to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Meta-analysis of three population-based genome-wide association studies (GWASs) comprising 4,069 children with glioma and 8,778 controls of multiple genetic ancestries. Replication was performed in a separate case-control cohort. Quantitative trait loci analyses and a transcriptome-wide association study were conducted to assess possible links with brain tissue expression across 18,628 genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Common variants in CDKN2B-AS1 at 9p21.3 were significantly associated with astrocytoma, the most common subtype of glioma in children (rs573687, p-value 6.974e-10, OR 1.273, CI95 1.179-1.374). The association was driven by low-grade astrocytoma (p-value 3.815e-9) and exhibited unidirectional effects across all six genetic ancestries. For glioma overall, the association approached genome-wide significance (rs3731239, p-value 5.411e-8), while no significant association was observed for high-grade tumors. Predicted decreased brain tissue expression of CDKN2B was significantly associated with astrocytoma (p-value 8.090e-8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
In this population-based GWAS meta-analysis, we identify and replicate 9p21.3 (CDKN2B-AS1) as a risk locus for childhood astrocytoma, thereby establishing the first genome-wide significant evidence of common variant predisposition in pediatric neuro-oncology. We furthermore provide a functional basis for the association by showing a possible link to decreased brain tissue CDKN2B expression and substantiate that genetic susceptibility differs between low- and high-grade astrocytoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systemic interindividual epigenetic variation in humans is associated with transposable elements and under strong genetic control</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/systemic-interindividual-epigenetic-variation-in-humans-is-associated-with-transposable-elements-and-under-strong-genetic-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/systemic-interindividual-epigenetic-variation-in-humans-is-associated-with-transposable-elements-and-under-strong-genetic-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genetic variants can modulate phenotypic outcomes via epigenetic intermediates, for example at methylation quantitative trait loci (mQTL).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We present the first large-scale assessment of mQTL at human genomic regions selected for interindividual variation in CpG methylation, which we call correlated regions of systemic interindividual variation (CoRSIVs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These can be assayed in blood DNA and do not reflect interindividual variation in cellular composition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use target-capture bisulfite sequencing to assess DNA methylation at 4086 CoRSIVs in multiple tissues from each of 188 donors in the NIH Gene-Tissue Expression (GTEx) program. At CoRSIVs, DNA methylation in peripheral blood correlates with methylation and gene expression in internal organs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also discover unprecedented mQTL at these regions. Genetic influences on CoRSIV methylation are extremely strong (median R2=0.76), cumulatively comprising over 70-fold more human mQTL than detected in the most powerful previous study. Moreover, mQTL beta coefficients at CoRSIVs are highly skewed (i.e., the major allele predicts higher methylation).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both surprising findings are independently validated in a cohort of 47 non-GTEx individuals. Genomic regions flanking CoRSIVs show long-range enrichments for LINE-1 and LTR transposable elements; the skewed beta coefficients may therefore reflect evolutionary selection of genetic variants that promote their methylation and silencing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyses of GWAS summary statistics show that mQTL polymorphisms at CoRSIVs are associated with metabolic and other classes of disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A focus on systemic interindividual epigenetic variants, clearly enhanced in mQTL content, should likewise benefit studies attempting to link human epigenetic variation to the risk of disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporation of DNA methylation quantitative trait loci (mQTLs) in epigenome wide association analysis: application to birthweight effects in neonatal whole blood</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/incorporation_of_dna_methylation_quantitative_trait_loci_mqtls_in_epigenome_wide_association_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/incorporation_of_dna_methylation_quantitative_trait_loci_mqtls_in_epigenome_wide_association_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
Epigenome-wide association studies (EWAS) have helped to define the associations between DNA methylation and many clinicopathologic and developmental traits. Since DNA methylation is affected by genetic variation at certain loci, EWAS associations may be potentially influenced by genetic effects. However, a formal assessment of the value of incorporating genetic variation in EWAS evaluations is lacking especially for multiethnic populations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Using single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) from Illumina Omni Express or Affymetrix PMDA arrays and DNA methylation data from the Illumina 450 K or EPIC array from 1638 newborns of diverse genetic ancestries, we generated DNA methylation quantitative trait loci (mQTL) databases for both array types. We then investigated associations between neonatal DNA methylation and birthweight (incorporating gestational age) using EWAS modeling, and reported how EWAS results were influenced by controlling for mQTLs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
For CpGs on the 450 K array, an average of 15.4% CpGs were assigned as mQTLs, while on the EPIC array, 23.0% CpGs were matched to mQTLs (adjusted P value &amp;lt; 0.05). The CpGs associated with SNPs were enriched in the CpG island shore regions. Correcting for mQTLs in the EWAS model for birthweight helped to increase significance levels for top hits. For CpGs overlapping genes associated with birthweight-related pathways (nutrition metabolism, biosynthesis, for example), accounting for mQTLs changed their regression coefficients more dramatically (&amp;gt; 20%) than for other random CpGs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
DNA methylation levels at circa 20% CpGs in the genome were affected by common SNP genotypes. EWAS model fit significantly improved when taking these genetic effects into consideration. Genetic effects were stronger on CpGs overlapping genetic elements associated with control of gene expression.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meta-analysis of DNA methylation datasets shows aberrant DNA methylation of thyroid development or function genes in Down syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/meta-analysis_of_dna_methylation_datasets_shows_aberrant_dna_methylation_of_thyroid_development_or_function_genes_in_down_syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/meta-analysis_of_dna_methylation_datasets_shows_aberrant_dna_methylation_of_thyroid_development_or_function_genes_in_down_syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: In Down syndrome (DS) there is a high occurrence of congenital hypothyroidism (CH) and subclinical hypothyroidism (SH) early in life. The etiology of CH and early SH in DS remains unclear. Previous research has shown genome-wide transcriptional and epigenetic alterations in DS. Thus, we hypothesized that CH and early SH could be caused by epigenetically driven transcriptional downregulation of thyroid-related genes, through promoter region hypermethylation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We extracted whole blood DNA methylation (DNAm) profiles of DS and non-DS individuals from four independent Illumina array-based datasets (252 DS individuals and 519 non-DS individuals). The data were divided in a discovery and validation dataset. Epigenome-wide association analysis was performed using a linear regression model, after which we filtered for thyroid-related genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: In the discovery dataset, we identified significant associations for DS in 18 thyroid-related genes. 21 of 30 significant differentially methylated positions (DMPs) were also significant in the validation dataset. A meta-analysis of the discovery and validation datasets detected 31 DMPs, including 29 promoter-associated CpGs with identical direction of effect across the datasets, and two differentially methylated regions (DMRs). 27 DMPs were hypomethylated and promoter-associated. The mean methylation difference of hypomethylated thyroid-related DMPs decreased with age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Contrary to our hypothesis of generalized hypermethylation of promoter regions of thyroid-related genes – indicative of epigenetic silencing of promoters and subsequent transcriptional downregulation, causing the biochemical thyroid abnormalities in DS –, we found an enrichment of hypomethylated DMPs annotated to promoter regions of these genes. This suggests that CH and early SH in DS are not caused by differential methylation of thyroid-related genes.
Considering epigenetic regulation is dynamic, we hypothesize the observed thyroid-related gene DNAm changes could be a rescue phenomenon in an attempt to ameliorate the thyroid phenotype, through epigenetic upregulation of thyroid-related genes. This hypothesis is supported by the finding of decreasing methylation difference of thyroid-related genes with age. The prevalence of early SH declines with age, so hypothetically, epigenetic upregulation of thyroid-related genes also diminishes. While this study provides interesting insights, the exact origin of CH and early SH in DS remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNA methylation at birth in monozygotic twins discordant for pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/dna_methylation_at_birth_in_monozygotic_twins_discordant_for_pediatric_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aberrant DNA methylation constitutes a key feature of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia at diagnosis, however its role as a predisposing or early contributor to leukemia development remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we evaluate DNA methylation at birth in 41 leukemia-discordant monozygotic twin pairs using the Illumina EPIC array on archived neonatal blood spots to identify epigenetic variation associated with development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia, independent of genetic influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through conditional logistic regression we identify 240 significant probes and 10 regions associated with the discordant onset of leukemia. We identify a significant negative coefficient bias, indicating DNA hypomethylation in cases, across the array and enhanced in open sea, shelf/shore, and gene body regions compared to promoter and CpG island regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we show an association between global DNA hypomethylation and future development of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia across disease-discordant genetically identical twins, implying DNA hypomethylation may contribute more generally to leukemia risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Periconceptional folate intake influences DNA methylation at birth based on dietary source in an analysis of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia cases and controls</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
Periconceptional folate intake is associated with the establishment of DNA methylation in offspring; however, variations in this relationship by food sources versus folic acid supplements are not described. Also, maternal folate intake is associated with decreased risk of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), but the mechanism is not known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives
We evaluated the relationship between periconceptional folate intake by source and DNA methylation at birth in a cohort of pediatric ALL cases and controls in an epigenome-wide association study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Genome-wide DNA methylation status obtained from archived neonatal blood spots from pediatric ALL cases (n = 189) and controls (n = 205) in the California Childhood Leukemia Study (CCLS) from 1995–2008 was compared to periconceptional folate from total, food, and supplemental sources using multivariable linear regression. Further stratification was performed by income, education, ethnicity, and total folate intake. We evaluated variable DNA methylation response to periconceptional folate by ALL case status through an interaction term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Two significant differentially methylated probes (DMPs) were associated with food and supplemental periconceptional folate intake in all subjects (n = 394). The top differentially methylated region at the promoter region of DUSP22 demonstrated DNA hypermethylation in ALL cases but not controls in response to total and food folate intake. We further identified eight interaction term DMPs with variable DNA methylation response to folate intake by ALL case status. Further stratification of the cohort by education and ethnicity revealed a substantially higher number of DMPs associated with supplemental folic acid intake in Hispanic subjects with lower income and education level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions
We identified modest associations between periconceptional folate intake and DNA methylation differing by source, including variation by ALL case status. Hispanic subjects of lower income and education appear uniquely responsive to periconceptional folate supplementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localized variation in ancestral admixture identifies pilocytic astrocytoma risk loci among Latino children</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/localized_variation_in_ancestral_admixture_identifies_pilocytic_astrocytoma_risk_loci_among_latino_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/localized_variation_in_ancestral_admixture_identifies_pilocytic_astrocytoma_risk_loci_among_latino_children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pilocytic astrocytoma (PA) is the most common pediatric brain tumor. PA has at least a 50% higher incidence in populations of European ancestry compared to other ancestral groups, which may be due in part to genetic differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first compared the global proportions of European, African, and Amerindian ancestries in 301 PA cases and 1185 controls of self-identified Latino ethnicity from the California Biobank. We then conducted admixture mapping analysis to assess PA risk with local ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found PA cases had a significantly higher proportion of global European ancestry than controls (case median = 0.55, control median = 0.51, P value = 3.5x10-3). Admixture mapping identified 13 SNPs in the 6q14.3 region (SNX14) contributing to risk, as well as three other peaks approaching significance on chromosomes 7, 10 and 13. Downstream fine mapping in these regions revealed several SNPs potentially contributing to childhood PA risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a significant difference in genomic ancestry associated with Latino PA risk and several genomic loci potentially mediating this risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatal cytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between HLA genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups.
For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio [OR] = 0.59; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.49-0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient = 0.13; 95% CI, 0.04-0.22).
HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR = 0.63; 95% CI, 0.38-1.01), although they had a lower tumor necrosis factor-α level (coefficient = −0.27; 95% CI, −0.49 to −0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk or cytokine levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating DNA methylation as a mediator of genetic risk in childhood acute lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/investigating_dna_methylation_as_a_mediator_of_genetic_risk_in_childhood_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/investigating_dna_methylation_as_a_mediator_of_genetic_risk_in_childhood_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified a growing number of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) associated with childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), yet the functional roles of most SNPs are unclear. Multiple lines of evidence suggest epigenetic mechanisms may mediate the impact of heritable genetic variation on phenotypes.
Here, we investigated whether DNA methylation mediates the effect of genetic risk loci for childhood ALL. We performed an epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) including 808 childhood ALL cases and 919 controls from California-based studies using neonatal blood DNA.
For differentially methylated CpG positions (DMPs), we next conducted association analysis with 23 known ALL risk SNPs followed by causal mediation analyses addressing the significant SNP-DMP pairs.
DNA methylation at CpG cg01139861, in the promoter region of IKZF1, mediated the effects of the intronic IKZF1 risk SNP rs78396808, with the average causal mediation effect (ACME) explaining ~ 30% of the total effect (ACME P = 0.0031).
In analyses stratified by self-reported race/ethnicity, the mediation effect was only significant in Latinos, explaining ~ 41% of the total effect of rs78396808 on ALL risk (ACME P = 0.0037). Conditional analyses confirmed the presence of at least three independent genetic risk loci for childhood ALL at IKZF1, with rs78396808 unique to non-European populations.
We also demonstrated that the most significant DMP in the EWAS, CpG cg13344587 at gene ARID5B (P = 8.61x10−10), was entirely confounded by the ARID5B ALL risk SNP rs7090445.
Our findings provide new insights into the functional pathways of ALL risk SNPs and the DNA methylation differences associated with risk of childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated epigenetic aging in newborns with Down syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/accelerated-epigenetic-aging-in-newborns-with-down-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accelerated aging is a hallmark of Down syndrome (DS), with adults experiencing early-onset Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease and premature aging of the skin, hair, and immune and endocrine systems. Accelerated epigenetic aging has been found in the blood and brain tissue of adults with DS but when premature aging in DS begins remains unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We investigated whether accelerated aging in DS is already detectable in blood at birth. We assessed the association between age acceleration and DS using five epigenetic clocks in 346 newborns with DS and 567 newborns without DS using Illumina MethylationEPIC DNA methylation array data. We compared two epigenetic aging clocks (DNAmSkinBloodClock and pan-tissue DNAmAge) and three epigenetic gestational age clocks (Haftorn, Knight, and Bohlin) between DS and non-DS newborns using linear regression adjusting for observed age, sex, batch, deconvoluted blood cell proportions, and genetic ancestry. Targeted sequencing of GATA1 was performed in a subset of 184 newborns with DS to identify somatic mutations associated with transient abnormal myelopoiesis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DS was significantly associated with increased DNAmSkinBloodClock (effect estimate = 0.2442, p &amp;lt; 0.0001), with an epigenetic age acceleration of 244 days in newborns with DS after adjusting for potential confounding factors (95% confidence interval: 196–292 days). We also found evidence of epigenetic age acceleration associated with somatic GATA1 mutations among newborns with DS (p = 0.015). DS was not associated with epigenetic gestational age acceleration. We demonstrate that accelerated epigenetic aging in the blood of DS patients begins prenatally, with implications for the pathophysiology of immunosenescence and other aging-related traits in DS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome-Wide Association Study of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children with Down Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-letter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome (DS) is caused by constitutional trisomy of chromosome 21 and is associated with an up to 30-fold increased risk of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL). While DS is associated with alterations in epigenetic markers, including DNA methylation, and gene expression. These mechanisms have not been fully explored in relation to DS-ALL etiology. Because the epigenome is sensitive to genetic and environmental influences during fetal development and can be leveraged to characterize blood cell proportions, we sought to evaluate the role of the neonatal methylome in children with DS on subsequent ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial 1555 G&gt;A Variant as a Potential Risk Factor for Childhood Glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:
Childhood glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is a highly aggressive disease with low survival, and its etiology, especially concerning germline genetic risk, is poorly understood. Mitochondria play a key role in putative tumorigenic processes relating to cellular oxidative metabolism, and mitochondrial DNA variants were not previously assessed for association with pediatric brain tumor risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods:
We conducted an analysis of 675 mitochondrial DNA variants in 90 childhood GBM cases and 2,789 controls to identify enrichment of mitochondrial variant associated with GBM risk. We also performed this analysis for other glioma subtypes including pilocytic astrocytoma. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants were also analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:
We identified m1555 A&amp;gt;G was significantly associated with GBM risk (adjusted OR 29.30, 95% CI 5.25-163.4, P value 9.5X10 -4). No association was detected for other subtypes. Haplotype analysis further supported the independent risk contributed by m1555 G&amp;gt;A, instead of a haplogroup joint effect. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants identified significant associations in European (rs62036057 in WWOX, adjusted OR = 2.99, 95% CI 1.88-4.75, P value = 3.42X10 -6) and Hispanic (rs111709726 in EFHD1, adjusted OR = 3.57, 95% CI 1.99-6.40, P value = 1.41X10 -6) populations in ethnicity-stratified analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:
We report for the first time a potential role played by a functional mitochondrial ribosomal RNA variant in childhood GBM risk, and a potential role for both mitochondrial and nuclear-mitochondrial DNA polymorphisms in GBM tumorigenesis. These data implicate cellular oxidative metabolic capacity as a contributor to the etiology of pediatric glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical characteristics of cytomegalovirus-positive pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia at diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-characteristics-of-cytomegalovirus-positive-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-at-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-characteristics-of-cytomegalovirus-positive-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-at-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infections and antigenic exposures during childhood are associated with pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) and are thought to lead to immune dysregulation stimulating pre-leukemic clones to expand and progress to overt leukemia. Emerging epidemiologic and laboratory evidence suggests cytomegalovirus (CMV) may contribute to the development of childhood ALL inspiring further investigative efforts and for the first time, identifying a specific target for ALL prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we aimed to better elucidate the role of CMV in ALL etiology by screening diagnostic leukemia bone marrow samples for CMV DNA using a highly quantitative droplet digital PCR (ddPCR) assay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified differences in demographic features and leukemia subtypes between CMV-positive and CMV-negative cases, supporting the hypothesis that CMV plays a role in ALL development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide trans-ethnic meta-analysis identifies novel susceptibility loci for childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/genome-wide-trans-ethnic-meta-analysis-identifies-novel-susceptibility-loci-for-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/genome-wide-trans-ethnic-meta-analysis-identifies-novel-susceptibility-loci-for-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We performed a trans-ethnic GWAS of childhood ALL in a discovery panel of 76,317 individuals, including 3482 cases and 72,835 controls distributed across four ethnic cohorts (African Americans, AFR; East Asian Americans, EAS; Latino Americans, LAT; Non-Latino White Americans, NLW; Supplemen- tary Information). After quality control filtering, our dataset consisted of 124, 318, 1878, 1162 cases and 2067, 5017, 8410, 57,341 controls in AFR, EAS, LAT, and NLW, respectively. Furthermore, we tested the association at 7,628,894 imputed SNPs, including low frequency (minor allele frequency, MAF, between 1–5%) variants that were not previously systematically tested. We aggregated summary statistics across the four ethnic groups in a fixed-effect meta- analysis. The genomic control inflation factor was 1.022 after excluding 16 previously reported ALL-associated loci, suggesting our meta-analysis was reasonably robust to any confounding due to population stratification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Biomarkers of Prenatal Tobacco Smoke Exposure Are Associated with Gene Deletions in Childhood Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Parental smoking is implicated in the etiology of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), the most common childhood cancer. We recently reported an association between an epigenetic biomarker of early-life tobacco smoke exposure at the AHRR gene and increased frequency of somatic gene deletions among ALL cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Here, we further assess this association using two epigenetic biomarkers for maternal smoking during pregnancy-DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and a recently established polyepigenetic smoking score-in an expanded set of 482 B-cell ALL (B-ALL) cases in the California Childhood Leukemia Study with available Illumina 450K or MethylationEPIC array data. Multivariable Poisson regression models were used to test the associations between the epigenetic biomarkers and gene deletion numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: We found an association between DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and deletion number among 284 childhood B-ALL cases with MethylationEPIC array data, with a ratio of means (RM) of 1.31 [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.02-1.69] for each 0.1 β value reduction in DNA methylation, an effect size similar to our previous report in an independent set of 198 B-ALL cases with 450K array data [meta-analysis summary RM (sRM) = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.10-1.57]. The polyepigenetic smoking score was positively associated with gene deletion frequency among all 482 B-ALL cases (sRM = 1.31 for each 4-unit increase in score; 95% CI, 1.09-1.57).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We provide further evidence that prenatal tobacco-smoke exposure may influence the generation of somatic copy-number deletions in childhood B-ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact: Analyses of deletion breakpoint sequences are required to further understand the mutagenic effects of tobacco smoke in childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medulloblastoma uses GABA transaminase to survive in the cerebrospinal fluid microenvironment and promote leptomeningeal dissemination</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summary:
Medulloblastoma (MB) is a malignant pediatric brain tumor arising in the cerebellum. Although abnormal GABAergic receptor activation has been described in MB, studies have not yet elucidated the contribution of receptor-independent GABA metabolism to MB pathogenesis. We find primary MB tumors globally display decreased expression of GABA transaminase (ABAT), the protein responsible for GABA metabolism, compared with normal cerebellum. However, less aggressive WNT and SHH subtypes express higher ABAT levels compared with metastatic G3 and G4 tumors. We show that elevated ABAT expression results in increased GABA catabolism, decreased tumor cell proliferation, and induction of metabolic and histone characteristics mirroring GABAergic neurons. Our studies suggest ABAT expression fluctuates depending on metabolite changes in the tumor microenvironment, with nutrient-poor conditions upregulating ABAT expression. We find metastatic MB cells require ABAT to maintain viability in the metabolite-scarce cerebrospinal fluid by using GABA as an energy source substitute, thereby facilitating leptomeningeal metastasis formation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The genome-wide impact of trisomy 21 on DNA methylation and its implications for hematopoiesis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome is associated with genome-wide perturbation of gene expression, which may be mediated by epigenetic changes. We perform an epigenome-wide association study on neonatal bloodspots comparing 196 newborns with Down syndrome and 439 newborns without Down syndrome, adjusting for cell-type heterogeneity, which identifies 652 epigenome-wide significant CpGs (P &amp;lt; 7.67 × 10−8) and 1,052 differentially methylated regions. Differential methylation at promoter/enhancer regions correlates with gene expression changes in Down syndrome versus non-Down syndrome fetal liver hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells (P &amp;lt; 0.0001). The top two differentially methylated regions overlap RUNX1 and FLI1, both important regulators of megakaryopoiesis and hematopoietic development, with significant hypermethylation at promoter regions of these two genes. Excluding Down syndrome newborns harboring preleukemic GATA1 mutations (N = 30), identified by targeted sequencing, has minimal impact on the epigenome-wide association study results. Down syndrome has profound, genome-wide effects on DNA methylation in hematopoietic cells in early life, which may contribute to the high frequency of hematological problems, including leukemia, in children with Down syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perioperative recovery in different urinary reconstruction approaches of radical cystectomy: Are the advantages of laparoscopy consistent? </title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/perioperative-recovery-in-different-urinary-reconstruction-approaches-of-radical-cystectomy-are-the-advantages-of-laparoscopy-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/perioperative-recovery-in-different-urinary-reconstruction-approaches-of-radical-cystectomy-are-the-advantages-of-laparoscopy-consistent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context: Radical cystectomy (RC) has complicated surgical procedures and various ways of urinary reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aims: The aim of this study is to investigate whether the advantages of laparoscopy over open surgery were consistent in the perioperative recovery of different methods of urinary diversion after RC in the general and the elderly (&amp;gt;65 years) population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Settings and design: A retrospective study reviewed 452 (elderly 261) patients who received RC from the year 2005-2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects and methods: Of all, 88 patients underwent laparoscopic RC (LRC) and 364 patients underwent open RC (ORC). There were 325 patients received ileal conduit (IC), whereas 127 patients received cutaneous ureterostomy (CU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical analysis used: We used different statistical methods (t-test, Chi-square, etc.) to compare variables outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: For IC urinary diversion, the general patients undergoing LRC had less intra-operative blood loss (566.5 vs. 1320.3 ml, P &amp;lt; 0.001), lower blood transfusion rate (11.4 vs. 34.1%, P &amp;lt; 0.001), shorter gastrointestinal recovery time (5.7 vs. 6.7 days, P= 0.002) and shorter length of hospital stay (LOS) (21.7 vs. 26.0 days, P = 0.003) than patients receiving ORC. Similar trends were observed in older patients. For CU urinary diversion, the general and the elderly patients receiving LRC had a shorter mean time to gastrointestinal recovery (P = 0.017, P &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively) than patients receiving ORC. No differences were found between LRC and ORC in intra-operative blood loss, allogeneic blood transfusion rate and LOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: In the general and the elderly population, laparoscopic approach could result in more rapid rehabilitation for RC patients, especially in the IC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Laparoscopy; perioperative care; radical cystectomy; urinary diversion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and Pathological Features of Prostatic Stromal Tumor of Uncertain Malignant Potential: A Retrospective Study of 23 Chinese Cases</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Prostatic stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) is a rare disease that may coexist with prostate stromal sarcoma (PSS). We aimed to analyze the histological and clinical features of STUMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Twenty-three patients diagnosed with STUMP from 2008 to 2019 were included. Clinicopathological and follow-up information was collected. In the subgroup analysis, we divided the patients into a pure STUMP group (N = 18) and a mixed STUMP (STUMP coexisting with PSS) group (N = 5). Student&amp;rsquo;s t test was used to compare the 2 groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Patients had a mean age of 55.5 ± 19.4 years and an average follow-up time of 42.3 months. The mean prostate volume was 109.2 ± 73.5 cm3, and the mean prostate-specific antigen was 8.03 ± 10.5 ng/mL. In the subgroup analysis, 16.7% (2/12) of pure STUMP patients had disease progression, while 100% (3/3) of mixed STUMP patients suffered from recurrence. Compared with the pure STUMP group, the mixed STUMP group was younger (37.2 vs. 60.6 years, p = 0.013) and had lower expression of estrogen receptor and progesterone receptor (p = 0.004 and p &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: STUMP is a rare disease with a relatively good prognosis. However, there is still a possibility of disease progression or coexistence with stromal sarcoma. Timely diagnosis and regular monitoring may be helpful in improving treatment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Hyperplasia; Prognosis; Prostate; Stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inflammation patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: The distribution characteristics of inflammatory cells in hyperplastic prostatic tissue and its influences on disease development remain unknown. We aimed to explore the infiltration characteristics of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) in combination with clinical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: The present study included 76 cases of BPH patients underwent transurethral resection of prostate (TURP). Hematoxylin-eosin staining was performed to identify the degree of general inflammation in prostatic tissues. The infiltration of T-lymphocytes (CD3), B-lymphocytes (CD20), and macrophages (CD68) were recorded by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The present study included 76 BPH patients with the mean age of 69.5 years old (range, 49-83 years) and the mean prostate volume of 91.9 mL (range, 24-218 mL). Periglandular inflammation was the most common pattern, being presented in 94.7% (72/76) patients, followed by stromal inflammation (67/76, 88.2%) and glandular inflammation (57/76, 75.0%). However, the stroma presented the highest rate of severe inflammation (14.6%). And the grades of glandular inflammation and stromal inflammation were independently correlated with prostate volume. T-lymphocytes, B-lymphocytes and macrophages had different infiltrated patterns in histological structures of prostate. And stromal hyperplasia dominated BPH was only significantly correlated with the T-lymphocytes infiltration condition (P=0.001). Meanwhile, overweight patients had more severe glandular inflammation in the prostate (P=0.010). The grade of glandular inflammation could independently increase prostate-specific antigen (PSA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We characterized infiltrated patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues from surgically treated BPH specimens. The role of inflammation in BPH development was highlighted by its correlation with the prostate volume, metabolism and PSA level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: B-lymphocytes; Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH); T-lymphocytes; inflammation; macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression and prognostic value of PD-L1 in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder squamous cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-and-prognostic-value-of-pd-l1-in-non-schistosoma-associated-urinary-bladder-squamous-cell-carcinoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-and-prognostic-value-of-pd-l1-in-non-schistosoma-associated-urinary-bladder-squamous-cell-carcinoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder squamous cell carcinoma (SqCC) has low incidence and is associated with chronic inflammation. Due to its unique etiology and pathology, expression of programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) in SqCC could be different from that of urothelial carcinoma, which may contribute to different responses to immunotherapy. In this study, we intended to explore the expression profile and prognostic value of PD-L1 in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder SqCC under the consideration of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes&amp;rsquo; (TILs) density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We conducted a retrospective study to review 604 bladder cancer patients who received radical cystectomy (RC) from 2009 to 2013 in Peking University First Hospital. We enrolled 67 bladder SqCC patients in total, including pure SqCC (n=19) and mixed SqCC (n=48, with urothelial carcinoma). PD-L1 protein expression and TILs density were evaluated by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Nine female and 58 male patients (median age 67.4 years) were enrolled in the present study. There were 15 stage T1-2 patients and 52 stage T3-4 patients. 27 patients had N1-2 lymph node metastasis. Overall, 61.2% cases were PD-L1-positive. Dense TILs coincided with higher PD-L1 expression rate. Median survival time of PD-L1 positive cases was significantly higher than negative cases (P=0.026). During multivariate analysis, positive PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were independent protective factors affecting overall survival (OS, PD-L1: P=0.022; TILs: P=0.010) and progression free survival (PFS, PD-L1: P=0.018; TILs: P=0.009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were frequently detected in urinary bladder SqCC tumors. Positive PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were correlated with better survival outcomes in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder SqCC. The immunotherapy targeting PD-L1 might be helpful to bladder SqCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Bladder cancer; programmed death ligand-1; squamous cell carcinoma (SqCC); survival; tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of CT-based radiomics in predicting portal pressure and patient outcome in portal hypertension</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/application-of-ct-based-radiomics-in-predicting-portal-pressure-and-patient-outcome-in-portal-hypertension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/application-of-ct-based-radiomics-in-predicting-portal-pressure-and-patient-outcome-in-portal-hypertension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portal venous pressure (PVP) measurement is of clinical significance, especially in patients with portal hypertension. However, the invasive nature and associated complications limits its application. The aim of the study is to propose a noninvasive predictive model of PVP values based on CT-extracted radiomic features.
Methods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiomics PVP (rPVP) models based on liver, spleen and combined features were established on an experimental cohort of 169 subjects. Radiomics features were extracted from each ROI and reduced via the LASSO regression to achieve an optimal predictive formula. A validation cohort of 62 patients treated for gastroesophageal varices (GOV) was used to confirm the utility of rPVP in predicting variceal recurrence. The association between rPVP and response to treatment was observed.
Results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three separate predictive formula for PVP were derived from radiomics features. rPVP was significantly correlated to patient response to endoscopic treatment for GOV. Among which, the model containing both liver and spleen features has the highest predictability of variceal recurrence, with an optimal cut-off value at 29.102 mmHg (AUC 0.866). A Kaplan Meier analysis further confirmed the difference between patients with varying rPVP values.
Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PVP values can be accurately predicted by a non-invasive, CT derived radiomics model. rPVP serves as a non-invasive and precise reference for predicting treatment outcome for GOV secondary to portal hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic syndrome is associated with improved cancer-specific survival in patients with localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Metabolic syndrome (MetS) has been found to be prevalent in cancer and have implications in cancer outcomes. In this study, we attempted to evaluate the prognostic value of MetS in localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC) patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We retrospectively collected clinicopathological data and pre-treatment laboratory test results of 480 patients with localized (T1-2N0M0) ccRCC undergoing radical or partial nephrectomy in Peking University First Hospital. MetS was diagnosed by criteria of the 2004 Chinese Medical Association Diabetes Society. Univariate and multivariate analyses were conducted to analyze the association between clinicopathological characteristics, MetS, and disease outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: In our cohort, 136 patients (28.3%) were diagnosed with MetS. Among them, 113 (83.1%) were men, suggesting that men were more likely to have MetS. This syndrome was also associated with increased pre-treatment creatinine levels. Median follow-up time was 70 months (range, 1-118 months) and 5-year overall survival (OS) rate was 92%. MetS was an independent favorable factor of cancer-specific survival (CSS) (P=0.017), and similar results were observed in Fuhrman nuclear grade 1-2 ccRCC patients by further analysis. Neither of the four components of the MetS (hypertension, diabetes mellitus, overweight/obesity and dyslipidemia) was an independent predictor of CSS. Patients who met more than 3 of the 4 criteria for MetS had higher CSS than those who met fewer than 2 criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: MetS is an independent prognostic factor for better CSS in localized ccRCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Metabolic syndrome (MetS); cancer-specific survival (CSS); prognosis; renal cell carcinoma (RCC).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prognostic value of preoperative serum albumin-globulin ratio for high-grade bladder urothelial carcinoma treated with radical cystectomy: A propensity score-matched analysis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-prognostic-value-of-preoperative-serum-albumin-globulin-ratio-for-high-grade-bladder-urothelial-carcinoma-treated-with-radical-cystectomy-a-propensity-score-matched-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-prognostic-value-of-preoperative-serum-albumin-globulin-ratio-for-high-grade-bladder-urothelial-carcinoma-treated-with-radical-cystectomy-a-propensity-score-matched-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives: Albumin-globulin ratio (AGR) has been reported as an independent risk factor for survival outcomes of a variety of malignancies. We aimed to further examine the prognostic value of AGR for urothelial carcinoma of bladder (UCB) using a propensity score-matched (PSM) analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials and methods: The medical data of 189 high-grade UCB patients undergoing radical cystectomy were retrospectively reviewed. AGR was defined as the ratio of serum albumin to nonalbumins (serum total protein-albumin). The association of preoperative AGR with clinicopathologic characteristics and prognosis were assessed. Multivariate analyses using Cox regression models were applied to evaluate the independent prognostic factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The receiver operating curve analysis indicated 1.55 as the optimal cutoff value to define low or high AGR. In prematched cohorts, Kaplan-Meier analysis indicated that AGR lower than 1.55 was associated with poorer overall survival (OS), progression-free survival (PFS), and tumor-specific survival (TSS) (P &amp;lt; 0.001 for all). Multivariable cox analyses also showed that AGR lower than 1.55 were an independent risk factor for survival outcomes, including OS, PFS, and TSS (P &amp;lt; 0.01 for all). In particular, AGR lower than 1.55 remained its prognostic value after PSM analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Low AGR was a significant unfavorable factor for UCB patients treated with radical cystectomy. This viable parameter should be enrolled in the pretreatment risk stratification for UCB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression of CPEB4 in invasive ductal breast carcinoma and its prognostic significance</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aims
Cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding proteins (CPEBs) are RNA-binding proteins that regulate translation by inducing cytoplasmic polyadenylation. CPEB4 has been reported in association with tumor growth, vascularization, and invasion in several cancers. To date, the expression of CPEB4 with clinical prognosis of breast cancer was never reported before. We aim to investigate the expression of CPEB4 and its prognostic significance in invasive ductal breast carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Immunohistochemical staining of CPEB4 and estrogen receptor, progesterone receptor, and human epidermal growth factor receptor was performed in 107 invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) samples, and prognostic significance was evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
High expression of CPEB4 was observed in 48.6% of IDC samples. Elevated CPEB4 expression was possibly related to increased histological grading (P=0.037) and N stage (P&amp;lt;0.001). Patients with high expression of CPEB4 showed shorter overall survival (P=0.001). High CPEB4 expression was an independent prognostic factor for overall survival (P=0.022, hazard ratio =4.344, 95% confidence interval =1.235–15.283).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
High CPEB4 expression is associated with increased histological grading and N stage, and it can serve as an independent prognostic factor in IDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding protein 4, invasive ductal carcinoma, immunohistochemistry, prognosis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
