<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction-between-maternal-killer-immunoglobulin-like-receptors-and-offspring-hlas-and-susceptibility-of-childhood-all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatalcytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown, but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions. We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between human leukocyte antigen (HLA) genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II). We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups. For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio, OR=0.59; 95% confidence interval, CI:0.49, 0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient=0.13; 95%CI:0.04, 0.22). HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR=0.63; 95%CI:0.38, 1.01), however with lower TNF-􏰀 level (coefficient=-0.27; 95%CI:-0.49, -0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk, or cytokine levels. The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial 1555 G&gt;A Variant as a Potential Risk Factor for Childhood Glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:
Childhood glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is a highly aggressive disease with low survival, and its etiology, especially concerning germline genetic risk, is poorly understood. Mitochondria play a key role in putative tumorigenic processes relating to cellular oxidative metabolism, and mitochondrial DNA variants were not previously assessed for association with pediatric brain tumor risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods:
We conducted an analysis of 675 mitochondrial DNA variants in 90 childhood GBM cases and 2,789 controls to identify enrichment of mitochondrial variant associated with GBM risk. We also performed this analysis for other glioma subtypes including pilocytic astrocytoma. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants were also analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:
We identified m1555 A&amp;gt;G was significantly associated with GBM risk (adjusted OR 29.30, 95% CI 5.25-163.4, P value 9.5X10 -4). No association was detected for other subtypes. Haplotype analysis further supported the independent risk contributed by m1555 G&amp;gt;A, instead of a haplogroup joint effect. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants identified significant associations in European (rs62036057 in WWOX, adjusted OR = 2.99, 95% CI 1.88-4.75, P value = 3.42X10 -6) and Hispanic (rs111709726 in EFHD1, adjusted OR = 3.57, 95% CI 1.99-6.40, P value = 1.41X10 -6) populations in ethnicity-stratified analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:
We report for the first time a potential role played by a functional mitochondrial ribosomal RNA variant in childhood GBM risk, and a potential role for both mitochondrial and nuclear-mitochondrial DNA polymorphisms in GBM tumorigenesis. These data implicate cellular oxidative metabolic capacity as a contributor to the etiology of pediatric glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical characteristics of cytomegalovirus-positive pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia at diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-characteristics-of-cytomegalovirus-positive-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-at-diagnosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-characteristics-of-cytomegalovirus-positive-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-at-diagnosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Infections and antigenic exposures during childhood are associated with pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) and are thought to lead to immune dysregulation stimulating pre-leukemic clones to expand and progress to overt leukemia. Emerging epidemiologic and laboratory evidence suggests cytomegalovirus (CMV) may contribute to the development of childhood ALL inspiring further investigative efforts and for the first time, identifying a specific target for ALL prevention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we aimed to better elucidate the role of CMV in ALL etiology by screening diagnostic leukemia bone marrow samples for CMV DNA using a highly quantitative droplet digital PCR (ddPCR) assay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We identified differences in demographic features and leukemia subtypes between CMV-positive and CMV-negative cases, supporting the hypothesis that CMV plays a role in ALL development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenome-Wide Association Study of Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia in Children with Down Syndrome</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Down syndrome (DS) is associated with an up to 30-fold increased risk of B-cell acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), and DS-ALL patients have worse overall survival and increased long-term treatment-related health conditions compared with non-DS ALL patients. In a recent genome-wide association study of DS-ALL, established ALL genetic risk loci were associated with DS-ALL, with several single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) conferring a larger effect on ALL risk in the context of DS than in euploidy. We performed an epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) to elucidate whether epigenetic differences at birth are associated with risk of subsequent DS-ALL.
Methods: The DS-ALL Discovery Study included 147 DS-ALL cases and 198 DS controls from the International Study of Down Syndrome Acute Leukemia, with newborn dried bloodspots (DBS) obtained from California (n=326) and Washington state (n=19) biobanks. The DS-ALL Replication Study included 24 DS-ALL cases and 24 DS controls with newborn DBS from the Michigan Neonatal Biobank. DNA was isolated from DBS, bisulfite converted, and assayed using Illumina Infinium MethylationEPIC Beadchip genome-wide DNA methylation arrays. Raw data were processed using “minfi” and “noob” packages in R. Reference-based deconvolution of blood cell proportions was performed using the Identifying Optimal DNA methylation Libraries (IDOL) algorithm, using DNA methylation data from cord blood reference samples, to estimate proportions of B cells, T cells (CD4+ and CD8+), monocytes, granulocytes, natural killer cells, and nucleated red blood cells. We compared each cell type proportion between DS-ALL cases and DS controls using linear regression adjusting for sex, plate, and principal components (PCs) to account for genetic ancestry. To identify single CpG probes associated with DS-ALL risk, we performed a multiethnic EWAS of DS-ALL in each study using linear regression adjusting for sex, plate, and PCs related to: 1) cell-type proportions and 2) genetic ancestry. Differentially methylated regions (DMRs) were identified using DMRcate and comb-p methods. In the Discovery Study, genome-wide SNP array data were available for 131 cases and 130 controls, and data from targeted sequencing of somatic mutations in exons 2/3 of GATA1 were available for 184/198 DS controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Deconvolution of blood cell proportions in the DS-ALL Discovery Study showed significantly higher B cell proportions in newborns with DS who later developed ALL (mean=0.0128, sd=0.0151) compared with DS controls (mean=0.00826, sd=0.0115) (P=6.4x10-4, coefficient=0.0052). A significantly higher B cell proportion at birth was also found in DS-ALL cases in the independent Replication Study (cases mean=0.048, sd=0.024; controls mean=0.039, sd=0.028; P=0.03, coefficient=0.015). In the Discovery Study, the B cell difference remained significant (P=5.8x10-3) with a similar effect size (coefficient=0.0045) after removal of GATA1 mutation-positive DS controls (n=30). We also investigated whether DS-ALL risk SNPs at ARID5B, IKZF1, GATA3, and CDKN2A may confound the association, but the increased B cell proportions in DS-ALL remained significant and effect estimates slightly increased in SNP genotype-adjusted models (coefficient range:0.0055-0.0059). In the EWAS of DS-ALL, 9 CpGs reached epigenome-wide significance (P&amp;lt;7.67x10-8), including 2 CpGs overlapping the promoter of the tumor suppressor gene TRIM13, frequently deleted in B-CLL, although none of these showed evidence of association (P&amp;lt;0.05) in the Replication Study. We identified 125 DMRs associated with DS-ALL in the Discovery Study. For 3 DMRs, overlapping genes HOPX, SMIM24, and PPP1R10, all implicated in normal and leukemic stem cell function, there were multiple significant CpGs in the Replication Study (P&amp;lt;0.05) all with effects in the same direction as the Discovery Study DMRs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: Increased B cell proportions in newborns with DS may be a risk factor for development of DS-ALL in childhood. This finding, based on DNA methylation data, requires confirmation using conventional cell count measures, and should be explored as a novel biomarker for ALL risk in the non-DS population. Single CpGs and DMRs associated with DS-ALL risk in our Discovery Study require further investigation, including in additional ALL case-control studies in DS and non-DS populations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genome-wide trans-ethnic meta-analysis identifies novel susceptibility loci for childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/genome-wide-trans-ethnic-meta-analysis-identifies-novel-susceptibility-loci-for-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/genome-wide-trans-ethnic-meta-analysis-identifies-novel-susceptibility-loci-for-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We performed a trans-ethnic GWAS of childhood ALL in a discovery panel of 76,317 individuals, including 3482 cases and 72,835 controls distributed across four ethnic cohorts (African Americans, AFR; East Asian Americans, EAS; Latino Americans, LAT; Non-Latino White Americans, NLW; Supplemen- tary Information). After quality control filtering, our dataset consisted of 124, 318, 1878, 1162 cases and 2067, 5017, 8410, 57,341 controls in AFR, EAS, LAT, and NLW, respectively. Furthermore, we tested the association at 7,628,894 imputed SNPs, including low frequency (minor allele frequency, MAF, between 1–5%) variants that were not previously systematically tested. We aggregated summary statistics across the four ethnic groups in a fixed-effect meta- analysis. The genomic control inflation factor was 1.022 after excluding 16 previously reported ALL-associated loci, suggesting our meta-analysis was reasonably robust to any confounding due to population stratification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Biomarkers of Prenatal Tobacco Smoke Exposure Are Associated with Gene Deletions in Childhood Acute Lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenetic-biomarkers-of-prenatal-tobacco-smoke-exposure-are-associated-with-gene-deletions-in-childhood-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Parental smoking is implicated in the etiology of acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), the most common childhood cancer. We recently reported an association between an epigenetic biomarker of early-life tobacco smoke exposure at the AHRR gene and increased frequency of somatic gene deletions among ALL cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Here, we further assess this association using two epigenetic biomarkers for maternal smoking during pregnancy-DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and a recently established polyepigenetic smoking score-in an expanded set of 482 B-cell ALL (B-ALL) cases in the California Childhood Leukemia Study with available Illumina 450K or MethylationEPIC array data. Multivariable Poisson regression models were used to test the associations between the epigenetic biomarkers and gene deletion numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: We found an association between DNA methylation at AHRR CpG cg05575921 and deletion number among 284 childhood B-ALL cases with MethylationEPIC array data, with a ratio of means (RM) of 1.31 [95% confidence interval (CI), 1.02-1.69] for each 0.1 β value reduction in DNA methylation, an effect size similar to our previous report in an independent set of 198 B-ALL cases with 450K array data [meta-analysis summary RM (sRM) = 1.32; 95% CI, 1.10-1.57]. The polyepigenetic smoking score was positively associated with gene deletion frequency among all 482 B-ALL cases (sRM = 1.31 for each 4-unit increase in score; 95% CI, 1.09-1.57).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We provide further evidence that prenatal tobacco-smoke exposure may influence the generation of somatic copy-number deletions in childhood B-ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Impact: Analyses of deletion breakpoint sequences are required to further understand the mutagenic effects of tobacco smoke in childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A genome-wide association analysis of childhood glioma and assessment of the contribution of enhanced European genetic risk via admixture analysis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/epigenome-wide-association-study-of-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-in-children-with-down-syndrome-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glioma is the most common brain tumor in children, comprising almost half of all pediatric central nervous system tumors. The biologic and histologic heterogeneity of pediatric glioma makes its treatment highly challenging. The incidence of glioma varies significantly by ethnicity, with higher rates observed in European populations, suggestive of genetic contributions. While the majority of gliomas are curable, high-grade malignant cases have poor survival rates, underscoring the importance of research in this common tumor affecting children. We aimed to identify genetic variants that are associated with childhood glioma and determine whether European genetic ancestry contributes to enhanced childhood glioma risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials and Methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted a genome-wide association study (GWAS) to identify genetic variants that are significantly associated with childhood glioma risk in a multi-ethnic California birth cohort (1982-2011). Study subjects included 3141 glioma cases (age 0-14 at diagnosis) and 3167 cancer-free controls matched by birth year, with additional 2913 controls from the 1000 Genomes Project and Human Genome Diversity Project. In subjects with pilocytic glioma, we also estimated the proportions of European, African and Native American ancestry proportions among admixed Hispanic subjects and tested whether genome wide European ancestry proportion is associated with risk. Regional admixture mapping and conditional analyses were performed to identify associations with local ancestral haplotypes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meta-analysis of GWAS in all ethnicities identified strong and significant hits in a specific noncoding RNA in chromosome 10. Global ancestry analysis demonstrated that a higher European ancestral background contributes to elevated childhood pilocytic astrocytoma risk (Wilcoxon rank sum test, P value = 0.003475). Regional admixture mapping revealed a locus in chromosome 6 (P value = 4.70×10^(-6)) as the most significant regional ancestry loci associated with pilocytic glioma risk, with additional contributions from other loci around the genome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We discover for the first time the genetic variants that are associated with childhood glioma risk, and captured the ancestral difference in glioma risk both globally and regionally. This latter analysis partly explains the demonstrated higher incidence and familial relative risk of low grade glioma in Europeans when compared to groups of other ancestral origins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medulloblastoma uses GABA transaminase to survive in the cerebrospinal fluid microenvironment and promote leptomeningeal dissemination</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summary:
Medulloblastoma (MB) is a malignant pediatric brain tumor arising in the cerebellum. Although abnormal GABAergic receptor activation has been described in MB, studies have not yet elucidated the contribution of receptor-independent GABA metabolism to MB pathogenesis. We find primary MB tumors globally display decreased expression of GABA transaminase (ABAT), the protein responsible for GABA metabolism, compared with normal cerebellum. However, less aggressive WNT and SHH subtypes express higher ABAT levels compared with metastatic G3 and G4 tumors. We show that elevated ABAT expression results in increased GABA catabolism, decreased tumor cell proliferation, and induction of metabolic and histone characteristics mirroring GABAergic neurons. Our studies suggest ABAT expression fluctuates depending on metabolite changes in the tumor microenvironment, with nutrient-poor conditions upregulating ABAT expression. We find metastatic MB cells require ABAT to maintain viability in the metabolite-scarce cerebrospinal fluid by using GABA as an energy source substitute, thereby facilitating leptomeningeal metastasis formation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The genome-wide impact of trisomy 21 on DNA methylation and its implications for hematopoiesis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-genome-wide-impact-of-trisomy-21-on-dna-methylation-and-its-implications-for-hematopoiesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down syndrome is associated with genome-wide perturbation of gene expression, which may be mediated by epigenetic changes. We perform an epigenome-wide association study on neonatal bloodspots comparing 196 newborns with Down syndrome and 439 newborns without Down syndrome, adjusting for cell-type heterogeneity, which identifies 652 epigenome-wide significant CpGs (P &amp;lt; 7.67 × 10−8) and 1,052 differentially methylated regions. Differential methylation at promoter/enhancer regions correlates with gene expression changes in Down syndrome versus non-Down syndrome fetal liver hematopoietic stem/progenitor cells (P &amp;lt; 0.0001). The top two differentially methylated regions overlap RUNX1 and FLI1, both important regulators of megakaryopoiesis and hematopoietic development, with significant hypermethylation at promoter regions of these two genes. Excluding Down syndrome newborns harboring preleukemic GATA1 mutations (N = 30), identified by targeted sequencing, has minimal impact on the epigenome-wide association study results. Down syndrome has profound, genome-wide effects on DNA methylation in hematopoietic cells in early life, which may contribute to the high frequency of hematological problems, including leukemia, in children with Down syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perioperative recovery in different urinary reconstruction approaches of radical cystectomy: Are the advantages of laparoscopy consistent? </title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/perioperative-recovery-in-different-urinary-reconstruction-approaches-of-radical-cystectomy-are-the-advantages-of-laparoscopy-consistent/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/perioperative-recovery-in-different-urinary-reconstruction-approaches-of-radical-cystectomy-are-the-advantages-of-laparoscopy-consistent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Context: Radical cystectomy (RC) has complicated surgical procedures and various ways of urinary reconstruction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aims: The aim of this study is to investigate whether the advantages of laparoscopy over open surgery were consistent in the perioperative recovery of different methods of urinary diversion after RC in the general and the elderly (&amp;gt;65 years) population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Settings and design: A retrospective study reviewed 452 (elderly 261) patients who received RC from the year 2005-2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subjects and methods: Of all, 88 patients underwent laparoscopic RC (LRC) and 364 patients underwent open RC (ORC). There were 325 patients received ileal conduit (IC), whereas 127 patients received cutaneous ureterostomy (CU).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistical analysis used: We used different statistical methods (t-test, Chi-square, etc.) to compare variables outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: For IC urinary diversion, the general patients undergoing LRC had less intra-operative blood loss (566.5 vs. 1320.3 ml, P &amp;lt; 0.001), lower blood transfusion rate (11.4 vs. 34.1%, P &amp;lt; 0.001), shorter gastrointestinal recovery time (5.7 vs. 6.7 days, P= 0.002) and shorter length of hospital stay (LOS) (21.7 vs. 26.0 days, P = 0.003) than patients receiving ORC. Similar trends were observed in older patients. For CU urinary diversion, the general and the elderly patients receiving LRC had a shorter mean time to gastrointestinal recovery (P = 0.017, P &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively) than patients receiving ORC. No differences were found between LRC and ORC in intra-operative blood loss, allogeneic blood transfusion rate and LOS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: In the general and the elderly population, laparoscopic approach could result in more rapid rehabilitation for RC patients, especially in the IC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Laparoscopy; perioperative care; radical cystectomy; urinary diversion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical and Pathological Features of Prostatic Stromal Tumor of Uncertain Malignant Potential: A Retrospective Study of 23 Chinese Cases</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/clinical-and-pathological-features-of-prostatic-stromal-tumor-of-uncertain-malignant-potential-a-retrospective-study-of-23-chinese-cases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Prostatic stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential (STUMP) is a rare disease that may coexist with prostate stromal sarcoma (PSS). We aimed to analyze the histological and clinical features of STUMP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: Twenty-three patients diagnosed with STUMP from 2008 to 2019 were included. Clinicopathological and follow-up information was collected. In the subgroup analysis, we divided the patients into a pure STUMP group (N = 18) and a mixed STUMP (STUMP coexisting with PSS) group (N = 5). Student&amp;rsquo;s t test was used to compare the 2 groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Patients had a mean age of 55.5 ± 19.4 years and an average follow-up time of 42.3 months. The mean prostate volume was 109.2 ± 73.5 cm3, and the mean prostate-specific antigen was 8.03 ± 10.5 ng/mL. In the subgroup analysis, 16.7% (2/12) of pure STUMP patients had disease progression, while 100% (3/3) of mixed STUMP patients suffered from recurrence. Compared with the pure STUMP group, the mixed STUMP group was younger (37.2 vs. 60.6 years, p = 0.013) and had lower expression of estrogen receptor and progesterone receptor (p = 0.004 and p &amp;lt; 0.001, respectively).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: STUMP is a rare disease with a relatively good prognosis. However, there is still a possibility of disease progression or coexistence with stromal sarcoma. Timely diagnosis and regular monitoring may be helpful in improving treatment outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Hyperplasia; Prognosis; Prostate; Stromal tumor of uncertain malignant potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The inflammation patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-inflammation-patterns-of-different-inflammatory-cells-in-histological-structures-of-hyperplasic-prostatic-tissues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: The distribution characteristics of inflammatory cells in hyperplastic prostatic tissue and its influences on disease development remain unknown. We aimed to explore the infiltration characteristics of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH) in combination with clinical data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: The present study included 76 cases of BPH patients underwent transurethral resection of prostate (TURP). Hematoxylin-eosin staining was performed to identify the degree of general inflammation in prostatic tissues. The infiltration of T-lymphocytes (CD3), B-lymphocytes (CD20), and macrophages (CD68) were recorded by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The present study included 76 BPH patients with the mean age of 69.5 years old (range, 49-83 years) and the mean prostate volume of 91.9 mL (range, 24-218 mL). Periglandular inflammation was the most common pattern, being presented in 94.7% (72/76) patients, followed by stromal inflammation (67/76, 88.2%) and glandular inflammation (57/76, 75.0%). However, the stroma presented the highest rate of severe inflammation (14.6%). And the grades of glandular inflammation and stromal inflammation were independently correlated with prostate volume. T-lymphocytes, B-lymphocytes and macrophages had different infiltrated patterns in histological structures of prostate. And stromal hyperplasia dominated BPH was only significantly correlated with the T-lymphocytes infiltration condition (P=0.001). Meanwhile, overweight patients had more severe glandular inflammation in the prostate (P=0.010). The grade of glandular inflammation could independently increase prostate-specific antigen (PSA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: We characterized infiltrated patterns of different inflammatory cells in histological structures of hyperplasic prostatic tissues from surgically treated BPH specimens. The role of inflammation in BPH development was highlighted by its correlation with the prostate volume, metabolism and PSA level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: B-lymphocytes; Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH); T-lymphocytes; inflammation; macrophages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression and prognostic value of PD-L1 in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder squamous cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-and-prognostic-value-of-pd-l1-in-non-schistosoma-associated-urinary-bladder-squamous-cell-carcinoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-and-prognostic-value-of-pd-l1-in-non-schistosoma-associated-urinary-bladder-squamous-cell-carcinoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder squamous cell carcinoma (SqCC) has low incidence and is associated with chronic inflammation. Due to its unique etiology and pathology, expression of programmed cell death ligand 1 (PD-L1) in SqCC could be different from that of urothelial carcinoma, which may contribute to different responses to immunotherapy. In this study, we intended to explore the expression profile and prognostic value of PD-L1 in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder SqCC under the consideration of tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes&amp;rsquo; (TILs) density.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We conducted a retrospective study to review 604 bladder cancer patients who received radical cystectomy (RC) from 2009 to 2013 in Peking University First Hospital. We enrolled 67 bladder SqCC patients in total, including pure SqCC (n=19) and mixed SqCC (n=48, with urothelial carcinoma). PD-L1 protein expression and TILs density were evaluated by immunohistochemistry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: Nine female and 58 male patients (median age 67.4 years) were enrolled in the present study. There were 15 stage T1-2 patients and 52 stage T3-4 patients. 27 patients had N1-2 lymph node metastasis. Overall, 61.2% cases were PD-L1-positive. Dense TILs coincided with higher PD-L1 expression rate. Median survival time of PD-L1 positive cases was significantly higher than negative cases (P=0.026). During multivariate analysis, positive PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were independent protective factors affecting overall survival (OS, PD-L1: P=0.022; TILs: P=0.010) and progression free survival (PFS, PD-L1: P=0.018; TILs: P=0.009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were frequently detected in urinary bladder SqCC tumors. Positive PD-L1 expression and dense TILs were correlated with better survival outcomes in non-schistosoma-associated urinary bladder SqCC. The immunotherapy targeting PD-L1 might be helpful to bladder SqCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Bladder cancer; programmed death ligand-1; squamous cell carcinoma (SqCC); survival; tumor-infiltrating lymphocytes (TILs).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Application of CT-based radiomics in predicting portal pressure and patient outcome in portal hypertension</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/application-of-ct-based-radiomics-in-predicting-portal-pressure-and-patient-outcome-in-portal-hypertension/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/application-of-ct-based-radiomics-in-predicting-portal-pressure-and-patient-outcome-in-portal-hypertension/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Purpose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portal venous pressure (PVP) measurement is of clinical significance, especially in patients with portal hypertension. However, the invasive nature and associated complications limits its application. The aim of the study is to propose a noninvasive predictive model of PVP values based on CT-extracted radiomic features.
Methods&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Radiomics PVP (rPVP) models based on liver, spleen and combined features were established on an experimental cohort of 169 subjects. Radiomics features were extracted from each ROI and reduced via the LASSO regression to achieve an optimal predictive formula. A validation cohort of 62 patients treated for gastroesophageal varices (GOV) was used to confirm the utility of rPVP in predicting variceal recurrence. The association between rPVP and response to treatment was observed.
Results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three separate predictive formula for PVP were derived from radiomics features. rPVP was significantly correlated to patient response to endoscopic treatment for GOV. Among which, the model containing both liver and spleen features has the highest predictability of variceal recurrence, with an optimal cut-off value at 29.102 mmHg (AUC 0.866). A Kaplan Meier analysis further confirmed the difference between patients with varying rPVP values.
Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PVP values can be accurately predicted by a non-invasive, CT derived radiomics model. rPVP serves as a non-invasive and precise reference for predicting treatment outcome for GOV secondary to portal hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metabolic syndrome is associated with improved cancer-specific survival in patients with localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/metabolic-syndrome-is-associated-with-improved-cancer-specific-survival-in-patients-with-localized-clear-cell-renal-cell-carcinoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Metabolic syndrome (MetS) has been found to be prevalent in cancer and have implications in cancer outcomes. In this study, we attempted to evaluate the prognostic value of MetS in localized clear cell renal cell carcinoma (ccRCC) patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods: We retrospectively collected clinicopathological data and pre-treatment laboratory test results of 480 patients with localized (T1-2N0M0) ccRCC undergoing radical or partial nephrectomy in Peking University First Hospital. MetS was diagnosed by criteria of the 2004 Chinese Medical Association Diabetes Society. Univariate and multivariate analyses were conducted to analyze the association between clinicopathological characteristics, MetS, and disease outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: In our cohort, 136 patients (28.3%) were diagnosed with MetS. Among them, 113 (83.1%) were men, suggesting that men were more likely to have MetS. This syndrome was also associated with increased pre-treatment creatinine levels. Median follow-up time was 70 months (range, 1-118 months) and 5-year overall survival (OS) rate was 92%. MetS was an independent favorable factor of cancer-specific survival (CSS) (P=0.017), and similar results were observed in Fuhrman nuclear grade 1-2 ccRCC patients by further analysis. Neither of the four components of the MetS (hypertension, diabetes mellitus, overweight/obesity and dyslipidemia) was an independent predictor of CSS. Patients who met more than 3 of the 4 criteria for MetS had higher CSS than those who met fewer than 2 criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions: MetS is an independent prognostic factor for better CSS in localized ccRCC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: Metabolic syndrome (MetS); cancer-specific survival (CSS); prognosis; renal cell carcinoma (RCC).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prognostic value of preoperative serum albumin-globulin ratio for high-grade bladder urothelial carcinoma treated with radical cystectomy: A propensity score-matched analysis</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-prognostic-value-of-preoperative-serum-albumin-globulin-ratio-for-high-grade-bladder-urothelial-carcinoma-treated-with-radical-cystectomy-a-propensity-score-matched-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/the-prognostic-value-of-preoperative-serum-albumin-globulin-ratio-for-high-grade-bladder-urothelial-carcinoma-treated-with-radical-cystectomy-a-propensity-score-matched-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives: Albumin-globulin ratio (AGR) has been reported as an independent risk factor for survival outcomes of a variety of malignancies. We aimed to further examine the prognostic value of AGR for urothelial carcinoma of bladder (UCB) using a propensity score-matched (PSM) analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Materials and methods: The medical data of 189 high-grade UCB patients undergoing radical cystectomy were retrospectively reviewed. AGR was defined as the ratio of serum albumin to nonalbumins (serum total protein-albumin). The association of preoperative AGR with clinicopathologic characteristics and prognosis were assessed. Multivariate analyses using Cox regression models were applied to evaluate the independent prognostic factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results: The receiver operating curve analysis indicated 1.55 as the optimal cutoff value to define low or high AGR. In prematched cohorts, Kaplan-Meier analysis indicated that AGR lower than 1.55 was associated with poorer overall survival (OS), progression-free survival (PFS), and tumor-specific survival (TSS) (P &amp;lt; 0.001 for all). Multivariable cox analyses also showed that AGR lower than 1.55 were an independent risk factor for survival outcomes, including OS, PFS, and TSS (P &amp;lt; 0.01 for all). In particular, AGR lower than 1.55 remained its prognostic value after PSM analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: Low AGR was a significant unfavorable factor for UCB patients treated with radical cystectomy. This viable parameter should be enrolled in the pretreatment risk stratification for UCB.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression of CPEB4 in invasive ductal breast carcinoma and its prognostic significance</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aims
Cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding proteins (CPEBs) are RNA-binding proteins that regulate translation by inducing cytoplasmic polyadenylation. CPEB4 has been reported in association with tumor growth, vascularization, and invasion in several cancers. To date, the expression of CPEB4 with clinical prognosis of breast cancer was never reported before. We aim to investigate the expression of CPEB4 and its prognostic significance in invasive ductal breast carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Immunohistochemical staining of CPEB4 and estrogen receptor, progesterone receptor, and human epidermal growth factor receptor was performed in 107 invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) samples, and prognostic significance was evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
High expression of CPEB4 was observed in 48.6% of IDC samples. Elevated CPEB4 expression was possibly related to increased histological grading (P=0.037) and N stage (P&amp;lt;0.001). Patients with high expression of CPEB4 showed shorter overall survival (P=0.001). High CPEB4 expression was an independent prognostic factor for overall survival (P=0.022, hazard ratio =4.344, 95% confidence interval =1.235–15.283).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
High CPEB4 expression is associated with increased histological grading and N stage, and it can serve as an independent prognostic factor in IDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding protein 4, invasive ductal carcinoma, immunohistochemistry, prognosis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
