<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brain tumor on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/tags/brain-tumor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in brain tumor on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/tags/brain-tumor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-ancestry genome-wide association study of 4,069 children with glioma identifies 9p21.3 risk locus</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
While recent sequencing studies have revealed that 10% of childhood gliomas are caused by rare germline mutations, the role of common variants is undetermined and no genome-wide significant risk loci for pediatric CNS tumors have been identified to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Meta-analysis of three population-based genome-wide association studies (GWASs) comprising 4,069 children with glioma and 8,778 controls of multiple genetic ancestries. Replication was performed in a separate case-control cohort. Quantitative trait loci analyses and a transcriptome-wide association study were conducted to assess possible links with brain tissue expression across 18,628 genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Common variants in CDKN2B-AS1 at 9p21.3 were significantly associated with astrocytoma, the most common subtype of glioma in children (rs573687, p-value 6.974e-10, OR 1.273, CI95 1.179-1.374). The association was driven by low-grade astrocytoma (p-value 3.815e-9) and exhibited unidirectional effects across all six genetic ancestries. For glioma overall, the association approached genome-wide significance (rs3731239, p-value 5.411e-8), while no significant association was observed for high-grade tumors. Predicted decreased brain tissue expression of CDKN2B was significantly associated with astrocytoma (p-value 8.090e-8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
In this population-based GWAS meta-analysis, we identify and replicate 9p21.3 (CDKN2B-AS1) as a risk locus for childhood astrocytoma, thereby establishing the first genome-wide significant evidence of common variant predisposition in pediatric neuro-oncology. We furthermore provide a functional basis for the association by showing a possible link to decreased brain tissue CDKN2B expression and substantiate that genetic susceptibility differs between low- and high-grade astrocytoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Localized variation in ancestral admixture identifies pilocytic astrocytoma risk loci among Latino children</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/localized_variation_in_ancestral_admixture_identifies_pilocytic_astrocytoma_risk_loci_among_latino_children/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/localized_variation_in_ancestral_admixture_identifies_pilocytic_astrocytoma_risk_loci_among_latino_children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pilocytic astrocytoma (PA) is the most common pediatric brain tumor. PA has at least a 50% higher incidence in populations of European ancestry compared to other ancestral groups, which may be due in part to genetic differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first compared the global proportions of European, African, and Amerindian ancestries in 301 PA cases and 1185 controls of self-identified Latino ethnicity from the California Biobank. We then conducted admixture mapping analysis to assess PA risk with local ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We found PA cases had a significantly higher proportion of global European ancestry than controls (case median = 0.55, control median = 0.51, P value = 3.5x10-3). Admixture mapping identified 13 SNPs in the 6q14.3 region (SNX14) contributing to risk, as well as three other peaks approaching significance on chromosomes 7, 10 and 13. Downstream fine mapping in these regions revealed several SNPs potentially contributing to childhood PA risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a significant difference in genomic ancestry associated with Latino PA risk and several genomic loci potentially mediating this risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitochondrial 1555 G&gt;A Variant as a Potential Risk Factor for Childhood Glioblastoma</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/mitochondrial-1555-ga-variant-as-a-potential-risk-factor-for-childhood-glioblastoma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background:
Childhood glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is a highly aggressive disease with low survival, and its etiology, especially concerning germline genetic risk, is poorly understood. Mitochondria play a key role in putative tumorigenic processes relating to cellular oxidative metabolism, and mitochondrial DNA variants were not previously assessed for association with pediatric brain tumor risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods:
We conducted an analysis of 675 mitochondrial DNA variants in 90 childhood GBM cases and 2,789 controls to identify enrichment of mitochondrial variant associated with GBM risk. We also performed this analysis for other glioma subtypes including pilocytic astrocytoma. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants were also analyzed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results:
We identified m1555 A&amp;gt;G was significantly associated with GBM risk (adjusted OR 29.30, 95% CI 5.25-163.4, P value 9.5X10 -4). No association was detected for other subtypes. Haplotype analysis further supported the independent risk contributed by m1555 G&amp;gt;A, instead of a haplogroup joint effect. Nuclear-encoded mitochondrial gene variants identified significant associations in European (rs62036057 in WWOX, adjusted OR = 2.99, 95% CI 1.88-4.75, P value = 3.42X10 -6) and Hispanic (rs111709726 in EFHD1, adjusted OR = 3.57, 95% CI 1.99-6.40, P value = 1.41X10 -6) populations in ethnicity-stratified analyses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion:
We report for the first time a potential role played by a functional mitochondrial ribosomal RNA variant in childhood GBM risk, and a potential role for both mitochondrial and nuclear-mitochondrial DNA polymorphisms in GBM tumorigenesis. These data implicate cellular oxidative metabolic capacity as a contributor to the etiology of pediatric glioblastoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medulloblastoma uses GABA transaminase to survive in the cerebrospinal fluid microenvironment and promote leptomeningeal dissemination</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/medulloblastoma-uses-gaba-transaminase-to-survive-in-the-cerebrospinal-fluid-microenvironment-and-promote-leptomeningeal-dissemination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Summary:
Medulloblastoma (MB) is a malignant pediatric brain tumor arising in the cerebellum. Although abnormal GABAergic receptor activation has been described in MB, studies have not yet elucidated the contribution of receptor-independent GABA metabolism to MB pathogenesis. We find primary MB tumors globally display decreased expression of GABA transaminase (ABAT), the protein responsible for GABA metabolism, compared with normal cerebellum. However, less aggressive WNT and SHH subtypes express higher ABAT levels compared with metastatic G3 and G4 tumors. We show that elevated ABAT expression results in increased GABA catabolism, decreased tumor cell proliferation, and induction of metabolic and histone characteristics mirroring GABAergic neurons. Our studies suggest ABAT expression fluctuates depending on metabolite changes in the tumor microenvironment, with nutrient-poor conditions upregulating ABAT expression. We find metastatic MB cells require ABAT to maintain viability in the metabolite-scarce cerebrospinal fluid by using GABA as an energy source substitute, thereby facilitating leptomeningeal metastasis formation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
