<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xin Wen on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/xin-wen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Xin Wen on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/xin-wen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Expression of CPEB4 in invasive ductal breast carcinoma and its prognostic significance</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/expression-of-cpeb4-in-invasive-ductal-breast-carcinoma-and-its-prognostic-significance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Abstract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aims
Cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding proteins (CPEBs) are RNA-binding proteins that regulate translation by inducing cytoplasmic polyadenylation. CPEB4 has been reported in association with tumor growth, vascularization, and invasion in several cancers. To date, the expression of CPEB4 with clinical prognosis of breast cancer was never reported before. We aim to investigate the expression of CPEB4 and its prognostic significance in invasive ductal breast carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Immunohistochemical staining of CPEB4 and estrogen receptor, progesterone receptor, and human epidermal growth factor receptor was performed in 107 invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC) samples, and prognostic significance was evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
High expression of CPEB4 was observed in 48.6% of IDC samples. Elevated CPEB4 expression was possibly related to increased histological grading (P=0.037) and N stage (P&amp;lt;0.001). Patients with high expression of CPEB4 showed shorter overall survival (P=0.001). High CPEB4 expression was an independent prognostic factor for overall survival (P=0.022, hazard ratio =4.344, 95% confidence interval =1.235–15.283).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
High CPEB4 expression is associated with increased histological grading and N stage, and it can serve as an independent prognostic factor in IDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords: cytoplasmic polyadenylation element binding protein 4, invasive ductal carcinoma, immunohistochemistry, prognosis&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
