<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adam J de Smith on Sebastian Li</title>
    <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/adam-j-de-smith/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adam J de Smith on Sebastian Li</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://sebastian-li.github.io/authors/adam-j-de-smith/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-ancestry genome-wide association study of 4,069 children with glioma identifies 9p21.3 risk locus</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/multi_ancestry_genome_wide_association_study_of_4069_children_with_glioma_identifies_9p21_3_risk_locus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
While recent sequencing studies have revealed that 10% of childhood gliomas are caused by rare germline mutations, the role of common variants is undetermined and no genome-wide significant risk loci for pediatric CNS tumors have been identified to date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Meta-analysis of three population-based genome-wide association studies (GWASs) comprising 4,069 children with glioma and 8,778 controls of multiple genetic ancestries. Replication was performed in a separate case-control cohort. Quantitative trait loci analyses and a transcriptome-wide association study were conducted to assess possible links with brain tissue expression across 18,628 genes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Common variants in CDKN2B-AS1 at 9p21.3 were significantly associated with astrocytoma, the most common subtype of glioma in children (rs573687, p-value 6.974e-10, OR 1.273, CI95 1.179-1.374). The association was driven by low-grade astrocytoma (p-value 3.815e-9) and exhibited unidirectional effects across all six genetic ancestries. For glioma overall, the association approached genome-wide significance (rs3731239, p-value 5.411e-8), while no significant association was observed for high-grade tumors. Predicted decreased brain tissue expression of CDKN2B was significantly associated with astrocytoma (p-value 8.090e-8).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion
In this population-based GWAS meta-analysis, we identify and replicate 9p21.3 (CDKN2B-AS1) as a risk locus for childhood astrocytoma, thereby establishing the first genome-wide significant evidence of common variant predisposition in pediatric neuro-oncology. We furthermore provide a functional basis for the association by showing a possible link to decreased brain tissue CDKN2B expression and substantiate that genetic susceptibility differs between low- and high-grade astrocytoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Periconceptional folate intake influences DNA methylation at birth based on dietary source in an analysis of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia cases and controls</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/periconceptional-folate-intake-influences-dna-methylation-at-birth-based-on-dietary-source-in-an-analysis-of-pediatric-acute-lymphoblastic-leukemia-cases-and-controls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Background
Periconceptional folate intake is associated with the establishment of DNA methylation in offspring; however, variations in this relationship by food sources versus folic acid supplements are not described. Also, maternal folate intake is associated with decreased risk of pediatric acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), but the mechanism is not known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Objectives
We evaluated the relationship between periconceptional folate intake by source and DNA methylation at birth in a cohort of pediatric ALL cases and controls in an epigenome-wide association study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods
Genome-wide DNA methylation status obtained from archived neonatal blood spots from pediatric ALL cases (n = 189) and controls (n = 205) in the California Childhood Leukemia Study (CCLS) from 1995–2008 was compared to periconceptional folate from total, food, and supplemental sources using multivariable linear regression. Further stratification was performed by income, education, ethnicity, and total folate intake. We evaluated variable DNA methylation response to periconceptional folate by ALL case status through an interaction term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Results
Two significant differentially methylated probes (DMPs) were associated with food and supplemental periconceptional folate intake in all subjects (n = 394). The top differentially methylated region at the promoter region of DUSP22 demonstrated DNA hypermethylation in ALL cases but not controls in response to total and food folate intake. We further identified eight interaction term DMPs with variable DNA methylation response to folate intake by ALL case status. Further stratification of the cohort by education and ethnicity revealed a substantially higher number of DMPs associated with supplemental folic acid intake in Hispanic subjects with lower income and education level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusions
We identified modest associations between periconceptional folate intake and DNA methylation differing by source, including variation by ALL case status. Hispanic subjects of lower income and education appear uniquely responsive to periconceptional folate supplementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interaction between maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptors and offspring HLAs and susceptibility of childhood ALL</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/interaction_between_maternal_killer_immunoglobulin-like_receptors_and_offspring_hlas_and_susceptibility_of_childhood_all/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL) in children is associated with a distinct neonatal cytokine profile. The basis of this neonatal immune phenotype is unknown but potentially related to maternal-fetal immune receptor interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We conducted a case-control study of 226 case child-mother pairs and 404 control child-mother pairs to evaluate the role of interaction between HLA genotypes in the offspring and maternal killer immunoglobulin-like receptor (KIR) genotypes in the etiology of childhood ALL, while considering potential mediation by neonatal cytokines and the immune-modulating enzyme arginase-II (ARG-II).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We observed different associations between offspring HLA-maternal KIR activating profiles and the risk of ALL in different predicted genetic ancestry groups.
For instance, in Latino subjects who experience the highest risk of childhood leukemia, activating profiles were significantly associated with a lower risk of childhood ALL (odds ratio [OR] = 0.59; 95% confidence interval [CI], 0.49-0.71) and a higher level of ARG-II at birth (coefficient = 0.13; 95% CI, 0.04-0.22).
HLA-KIR activating profiles were also associated with a lower risk of ALL in non-Latino Asians (OR = 0.63; 95% CI, 0.38-1.01), although they had a lower tumor necrosis factor-α level (coefficient = −0.27; 95% CI, −0.49 to −0.06). Among non-Latino White subjects, no significant association was observed between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and ALL risk or cytokine levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current study reports the association between offspring HLA-maternal KIR interaction and the development of childhood ALL with variation by predicted genetic ancestry. We also observed some associations between activating profiles and immune factors related to cytokine control; however, cytokines did not demonstrate causal mediation of the activating profiles on ALL risk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Investigating DNA methylation as a mediator of genetic risk in childhood acute lymphoblastic Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/investigating_dna_methylation_as_a_mediator_of_genetic_risk_in_childhood_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sebastian-li.github.io/publication/investigating_dna_methylation_as_a_mediator_of_genetic_risk_in_childhood_acute_lymphoblastic_leukemia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Genome-wide association studies have identified a growing number of single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) associated with childhood acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), yet the functional roles of most SNPs are unclear. Multiple lines of evidence suggest epigenetic mechanisms may mediate the impact of heritable genetic variation on phenotypes.
Here, we investigated whether DNA methylation mediates the effect of genetic risk loci for childhood ALL. We performed an epigenome-wide association study (EWAS) including 808 childhood ALL cases and 919 controls from California-based studies using neonatal blood DNA.
For differentially methylated CpG positions (DMPs), we next conducted association analysis with 23 known ALL risk SNPs followed by causal mediation analyses addressing the significant SNP-DMP pairs.
DNA methylation at CpG cg01139861, in the promoter region of IKZF1, mediated the effects of the intronic IKZF1 risk SNP rs78396808, with the average causal mediation effect (ACME) explaining ~ 30% of the total effect (ACME P = 0.0031).
In analyses stratified by self-reported race/ethnicity, the mediation effect was only significant in Latinos, explaining ~ 41% of the total effect of rs78396808 on ALL risk (ACME P = 0.0037). Conditional analyses confirmed the presence of at least three independent genetic risk loci for childhood ALL at IKZF1, with rs78396808 unique to non-European populations.
We also demonstrated that the most significant DMP in the EWAS, CpG cg13344587 at gene ARID5B (P = 8.61x10−10), was entirely confounded by the ARID5B ALL risk SNP rs7090445.
Our findings provide new insights into the functional pathways of ALL risk SNPs and the DNA methylation differences associated with risk of childhood ALL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
